music
音楽
applause
拍手
We invite you to the Institute of Molecular Biology of our hospital tonight
今夜あなたを当院分子生物学研究所にご招待します
The special evaluation researcher of the inspection team came to tell us
視察団の特別評価研究員が来て教えてくれた
Then we also have an online live broadcast
その後、オンライン生放送も行います
Teacher Na Jian graduated from the Department of Chemistry, National Taiwan University.
Na Jian 先生は国立台湾大学化学科を卒業しました。
Then went to the State University of New York to study for a Ph.D.
その後、博士号取得のためにニューヨーク州立大学に留学しました。
when he was a doctor
彼が医者だったとき
developed a very important experimental method
非常に重要な実験方法を開発した
The two-hybrid approach we call Filial Mother Army
私たちが「親孝行母軍」と呼ぶ 2 つのハイブリッド アプローチ
This is used to test the binding between protein and protein
タンパク質とタンパク質の結合をテストするために使用されます。
Because this method was later widely used
この方法は後に広く使われるようになったので、
It is a very important research tool in biology
それは生物学における非常に重要な研究ツールです
His teacher was elected a member of the American Academy of Sciences for this
彼の教師はこの功績によりアメリカ科学アカデミーの会員に選出された
This is what he did when he was a doctor
これは彼が医師だったときにやったことです
After his postdoctorate, he went to the Faculty of the University of California
博士研究員を取得した後、カリフォルニア大学の学部に進学しました。
Returned to the Institute of Molecular Biology of our school in 1996
1996年に本校分子生物学研究所に復帰
right in my lab we're next door
私の研究室のすぐ隣にいます
Teacher Jian’s research in recent years has not only done
ジャン先生の近年の研究は、
research institutes also research institutes
研究機関も研究機関
Returned to the Institute of Molecular Biology of our school in 1996
1996年に本校分子生物学研究所に復帰
right in my lab we're next door
私の研究室のすぐ隣にいます
Check teacher's research in recent years
先生の近年の研究をチェックする
In recent years, in addition to doing basic nervous system development
近年では、基礎的な神経系の発達を行うことに加えて、
also started to work on neurodegenerative diseases
神経変性疾患の治療も始めました
some related research
いくつかの関連研究
it has won many awards
多くの賞を受賞しています
Including our Academy's Young Scholar Book Award
アカデミーのヤング・スカラー・ブック賞を含む
Excellence Award from the Ministry of Science and Technology
科学技術省優秀賞を受賞
Academic Awards of the Ministry of Education Hou Jindui Research Award
教育部学術賞 侯真迪研究賞
Taiwan's Science and Technology Award
台湾科学技術賞
He also does a lot of service work
彼はサービス業もたくさんやっています
Including serving as the chairman of this basic neurological society in Taiwan
台湾の基礎神経学会の会長を務めるなど
Then he will tell us a very interesting topic today
それから彼は今日とても興味深い話をしてくれるでしょう
walking with neurologists
神経内科医と一緒に歩く
Then he's going to talk about fate, fairness and competition.
それから彼は運命、公平性、競争について話すつもりです。
From the aspects of learning, degeneration and medical treatment of the nervous system
神経系の学習、変性、治療の側面から
Then we welcome Teacher Shoulder
それでは、ショルダー先生をお迎えします
Okay, thank you grandson Mi for the introduction.
さて、孫のミーさん、紹介してくれてありがとう。
Then I came back to Taiwan for about 22 years
それから台湾に戻ってきて約22年。
That's very trustworthy and Sun Zimi is the laboratory next door
それはとても信頼できます、そして孫子美は隣の研究室です
It's always been the lab next door
いつも隣の研究室だった
So besides his family, the person he sees the most should be me
だから家族以外に彼が一番見ているのは私なんだろう
I am very happy that I can give a speech here today
今日はここでスピーチできることをとてもうれしく思います
Then this is a challenge for us
それでは、これは私たちにとっての挑戦です
Because it is a popular science speech
人気の科学講演だから
Then I'll try to put my research over the years
それから私は何年にもわたって私の研究を試みます
compare with what i think
私が考えていることと比較してください
My normal language to speak to you
あなたと話す私の通常の言語
but if it's too simple
でもそれが単純すぎると
Please forgive me too
私も許してください
Help me stop if it's too hard
難しすぎる場合は停止するのを手伝ってください
feel free to ask no problem
問題なくお気軽に質問してください
What I tell you today is
今日私が皆さんにお伝えすることは、
In fact, neurons
実はニューロンは、
neurons
ニューロン
This topic was first ordered by my students
このトピックは最初に私の生徒から注文されました
Because they said that there was a Korean movie called
という韓国映画があると言っていたからです。
"Rain God" is very popular
「雨の神様」が大人気
Me and some Korean drama students come to listen to this
私と韓国演劇の学生たちがこれを聴きに来ます
so i ordered one
それで私は一つ注文しました
Title of "Rain Neuron Pass"
タイトル「レインニューロンパス」
In fact we want to say
実際、私たちが言いたいのは、
look at nerve cells or neurons
神経細胞やニューロンを見てください
Its whole development and whole heredity
その発展全体と遺伝全体
how to decide its itinerary
旅程をどう決めるか
as if i'm next to you
まるで私があなたの隣にいるかのように
look at a nerve cell
神経細胞を見ている
From birth to differentiation to aging
誕生から分化、老化まで
process to death
死に至る過程
what the hell is a change
一体何が変わったのか
between cells
細胞間
And what is the relationship between cells and genes?
そして細胞と遺伝子の間にはどのような関係があるのでしょうか？
Interactions or what a regulation looks like
インタラクションまたは規制の概要
Then I returned to Taiwan 22 years ago
そして22年前に台湾に戻りました
Then go to the branch office
それから支店に行きます
Then the first thing is to get married and have children
それなら結婚して子供を産むのが先だ
And here are my two kids
そして、これが私の2人の子供です
That photo from 20 years ago
20年前のあの写真
Then the model organisms in our laboratory
それから私たちの研究室のモデル生物
is made with fruit flies
ショウジョウバエで作られています
Every model organism looking at the organisms of Drosophila
ショウジョウバエの生物を観察するすべてのモデル生物
Of course, watch your child grow up
もちろんお子様の成長も見守ります
This is actually a model organism
実はこれがモデル生物なんです
is a model organism for a person
人間のモデル生物です
then i feel very curious
それから私はとても興味があると感じます
You will find that these two children
この二人の子供たちは
why does it look so similar
なぜそんなに似ているのでしょうか
Of course, this is very simple.
もちろん、これは非常に簡単です。
Both parents have the same genes
両親は同じ遺伝子を持っています
The other point is that
もう一つの点は、
Except very...
非常に例外的に...
so we know that
だから私たちはそれを知っています
the process by which genes contribute to the formation of an organism
遺伝子が生物の形成に寄与するプロセス
In fact, it has a big, big impact like this
実はこれほど大きな影響があるのです
But the two are not exactly the same, right?
しかし、この 2 つはまったく同じではありませんよね?
Because their genes can't be exactly the same
遺伝子が全く同じになることはないから
There is a part of father and part of mother.
こういう父親の部分もあれば母親の部分もある
So this is what caused me to be interested in this gene
これが私がこの遺伝子に興味を持ったきっかけです
This one with the research topic of development...
開発の研究テーマを持つこれは...
At the same time, we also use nerve cells
同時に神経細胞も使います。
It is neurons that are the subject of this study
この研究の対象となるのはニューロンです
so before starting
だから始める前に
I'll tell you first
最初に言っておきます
easy
簡単
I think many people may also know
ご存知の方も多いかと思いますが、
But still take a little time
でも、まだ少し時間がかかります
with everyone
みんなとともに
ditch this
これを捨ててください
tell everyone about this
このことをみんなに伝えてください
The definition of a few simple nouns of neurons
ニューロンのいくつかの単純な名詞の定義
Then the definition of this noun you heard
それでは、あなたが聞いたこの名詞の定義は
You may be very clear to many people
あなたは多くの人にとって非常に明確かもしれません
but if you haven't heard
でも聞いていないなら
you can follow me
あなたは私をフォローできます
Let's memorize these words for a while
しばらくこの言葉を覚えてみましょう
it's easier to wait
待つ方が簡単です
You can memorize the process as I told you.
先ほど説明したプロセスを覚えておいてください。
Then the nerve cells seen here
そして、ここに見られる神経細胞
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Oh, the nerve cells
ああ、神経細胞ね
In fact, a nerve cell
実は神経細胞は
a cell
細胞
its own function
独自の機能
It's not really obvious
それはあまり明らかではありません
the nerve cells
神経細胞
one after the other
次々に
one after another
続々
Then such a nerve will form a
すると、そのような神経が形成されます。
So-called
所謂的
to connect together
一緒につながる
forming one
一つを形成する
network time
ネットワーク時間
it only has one
それは1つだけです
a function is here
関数はここにあります
So the nerve cells
それで神経細胞は
to be connected together
一緒につながること
basically i
基本的に私は
We can divide it into three parts from its type
その種類から3つの部分に分けることができます
You can see that this neuron
このニューロンが
The most important thing is a neural ontology
最も重要なことはニューラルオントロジーです
an ontology
オントロジー
just like its body itself
まるでその体そのもののように
This provides the entire nerve cell with very high
これにより、神経細胞全体に非常に高いエネルギーが供給されます。
may be some protein
タンパク質かもしれない
RNA or some kind of nutrient
RNA またはある種の栄養素
or something
か何か
so that the nerve can have a normal function like this
このように神経が正常に機能できるように
So there is a cell's body
つまり細胞の本体があるのです
In addition, there is a long plant called axon, which is very long
また、軸索と呼ばれる非常に長い植物があります。
The nerve cell itself has a very long one
神経細胞自体は非常に長いものです
we can see say
言うことがわかります
Almost every nerve cell has an axon like this
ほぼすべての神経細胞にはこのような軸索があります
The axon is actually what everyone remembers that the axon is a
軸索は実際には、軸索が
send a signal in one direction
一方向に信号を送信する
That is to say, the nerve cell body
つまり神経細胞そのもの
it sends the signal out
それは信号を送信します
sent out from the axon like this
このように軸索から送り出されます
sent to the next nerve cell
次の神経細胞に送られる
What part does the nerve cell receive
神経細胞はどの部分を受け取るのか
it's called speed
それはスピードと呼ばれます
just stand out
ただ目立つだけ
it's the other end
それはもう一方の端です
mostly the other end
ほとんど反対側の端
It has some quite forked
かなり分岐した部分もある
There are quite a lot of forks. This is called Sutu.
フォークがかなり多いのですが、これをスツといいます。
Then this old rabbit is receiving the signal
するとこの年老いたウサギが信号を受信して​​いる
So everyone remembers that there is an ontology
だから誰もがオントロジーがあることを覚えています
There's an axis rabbit, there's an old rabbit like this
軸ウサギがいる、こんな年寄りウサギがいる
Then the neuron can
するとニューロンは、
one after another
続々
So we see here that
ここで次のことが分かります
Here are two nerve cells
ここに2つの神経細胞があります
Then this is its body, the axis rabbit
では、これが本体、軸ウサギです
If the axis rabbit, the tail will be forked
軸ウサギなら尻尾は二股に分かれる
That's the rabbit with another cell
それは別の細胞を持つウサギです
it can be connected together
一緒に接続することができます
form a ratio of possibly several connections
おそらくいくつかの接続の比率を形成する
The place where this connection is called Tutu
このつながりが生まれる場所をTutuと呼ぶ
Because there is a place where the axis rabbit and the old rabbit come into contact
軸ウサギと老ウサギが触れ合う場所があるので
It's called Tutu
チュチュといいます
That's where the two pictures came out
そこで出てきたのが2枚の写真
The place of contact is called Tutu
連絡先はTutuと呼ばれます
that's where they communicate
そこが彼らのコミュニケーションの場です
This axis rabbit handles the signal
この軸のウサギは信号を処理します
a telegram
電報
And then to this point of contact
そしてこちらの連絡先へ
some chemical molecules
いくつかの化学分子
and then to the next neuron
そして次のニューロンへ
Receive the signal and pass it on
信号を受信して​​送信します
So we can say
だから言えることは
In our brain, there are actually many, many such nerve cells connected with nerve cells
私たちの脳には、実際にはこのような神経細胞がたくさんあり、神経細胞とつながっています。
Then pass the signal through to make a thing
次に信号を通過させて物を作ります
So we have a lot of new networks in our brains like this
私たちの脳にはこのような新しいネットワークがたくさんあります
You can say that it is a very complex network interaction effect
非常に複雑なネットワーク相互作用効果であると言えます。
we can ask
私たちは尋ねることができます
How many neurons are there in our brain
私たちの脳にはいくつのニューロンがあるのか
Then how much prominence
では、どのくらいの知名度があるのか
how many complex networks
複雑なネットワークはいくつありますか
In fact, people often compare the planets in this universe with the nerve cells in the brain
実際、人々はよくこの宇宙の惑星を脳の神経細胞と比較します。
Who is more like this
誰がもっとこれに似ていますか
This is of course I copied it from that Euclopedia
これはもちろん Eucpedia からコピーしたものです
That is to say, the star shape of the Milky Way is about 10 to the 11th power
つまり、天の川の星の形は約10の11乗です。
The star shape of the universe is about 10 to the 23rd power
宇宙の星の形は約10の23乗です
There are about 1011 grids of neurons in the brain
脳には約1011個のニューロングリッドがある
very very many
非常非常多
Each person's brain is about 10 to the 11th power
人の脳の大きさはおよそ10の11乗です
Then you are similar to the star shape of our Milky Way in the universe
そうすればあなたは宇宙の天の川の星の形に似ています
Neural gardens can form about a thousand
ニューラルガーデンは約1000個形成される
contact with another thousand neurons
別の千のニューロンとの接触
It's like a thousand synapses
それは千のシナプスのようなものです
So there are about 14 synapses
つまりシナプスは約14個あります
So it looks like it is much less than the stars in the universe
つまり、宇宙の星よりもはるかに小さいように見えます
The cells of this neural garden are almost as careful as tremella
この神経庭の細胞はトレメラとほぼ同じくらい慎重です
But then I thought
しかし、そのとき私は思いました
Hey, we're not alone
ねえ、私たちは一人じゃないよ
not alone in this world
この世界で一人ではない
there are so many people in our world
私たちの世界にはたくさんの人がいます
Then every person often we have some collective behaviors
そして、どの人も、集団的な行動をとることがよくあります。
Bubble our cultural creation
私たちの文化創造をバブル化する
scientific research
科学研究
So if we add up the synapses of humans all over the world
つまり、世界中の人間のシナプスを合計すると
only the 24th square
24マス目だけ
So this is actually a very large number.
したがって、これは実際には非常に大きな数です。
so for us to say
だから私たちが言うには
Hey, we want to study the structure of this neural garden
ねえ、この神経庭の構造を研究したいんだ
its birth its formation
その誕生、その形成
And what's the function of its whole connection together?
そして、その全体的なつながりはどのような役割を果たしているのでしょうか?
that's a very interesting subject
それはとても興味深いテーマです
Not only are there many nerve cells
神経細胞が多いだけではなく
In addition to so many nerve cells in our brain
私たちの脳には非常に多くの神経細胞があることに加えて、
We also have a lot of complex different
複雑で異なるものもたくさんあります
We have types of nerve cells
私たちは神経細胞の種類を持っています
Then let's show you this again
それでは、またお見せしましょう
there are many
沢山あります
show a very wide variety of nerve cells
非常に多様な神経細胞を示す
inside our brain
私たちの脳内で
Then you can see that there is a very simple
すると、非常に単純なことがわかります。
like this one
このように
We call it granule cells like this
このように顆粒細胞と呼びます
This accounts for more than 50% of the brain
これは脳の50％以上を占めます
Then of course we have very complex
もちろん、非常に複雑です
like this one in the cerebellum
これは小脳にあるものと同じです
Putin's One Cell
プーチン大統領のワンセル
you can see say
言うことがわかります
its quick burst
その素早いバースト
Sutu The Sutu we just talked about is the signal place
Sutu 先ほどの Sutu は信号所です
In fact, the bifurcation is very powerful.
実際、分岐は非常に強力です。
You can see that it keeps forking
分岐し続けていることがわかります
It really looks like a tree
本当に木みたいですね
and the motor neurons on our spine
そして私たちの脊椎の運動ニューロン
There are so many motor nerve cells in our spine
私たちの脊椎には非常に多くの運動神経細胞が存在します
Then you can see that it is also
そうすれば、それもあることがわかります
A nerve cell has many branches
神経細胞にはたくさんの枝があり、
Then finally inside our cerebral cortex
そして最後に大脳皮質の内部に
There are a lot of this so-called
こういったいわゆるものがたくさんあります
vertebral neurons
脊椎ニューロン
Then this is the same as our human beings later
それでは、これは後の私たち人間と同じです
A neuron involved in this cognitive aspect
この認知面に関与するニューロン
There are many such
そのようなものはたくさんあります
So we can see that in fact we
したがって、実際に私たちが
In addition to a lot of
たくさんのことに加えて、
outside of nerve cells
神経細胞の外側
We also have many different types of Shenyin cells
さまざまな種類の神陰細胞も取り揃えています
Well, this is actually a big problem for us.
実は、これは私たちにとって大きな問題なのです。
That is to say, in addition to the fact that our brains need to grow a lot of divine sound cells
つまり、私たちの脳は神聖な音細胞をたくさん成長させる必要があるという事実に加えて、
How do we control and grow different Shenyin cells?
さまざまな神音細胞をどのように制御し、増殖させるのでしょうか?
You can do different functions like this
このようにさまざまな機能を実行できます
throughout our development
私たちの開発全体を通して
Then how does this cause different Shenyin cells to come out?
では、これによりどのようにして異なる神陰細胞が出現するのでしょうか?
allows us to perform different jobs like this
このようなさまざまなジョブを実行できるようになります
Well, this is actually very complicated because the brain is too complicated
脳は複雑すぎるため、これは実際には非常に複雑です
Then too many different kinds of Shenyin cells
そうすると神陰細胞の種類が多すぎる
So my subjects are actually fruit flies.
つまり、私の被写体は実際にはショウジョウバエです。
Then we have to simplify the problem to say
次に、問題を単純化して次のように言う必要があります。
Then I will ask a Shenyin cell, a certain Shenyin cell
それから私は神陰細胞に尋ねます、ある神陰細胞に
How on earth did it grow and grow like this?
一体どうやってここまで成長し成長したのでしょうか？
Then we use a steel wool from a fruit fly
次にショウジョウバエから採取したスチールウールを使用します
It's called steel wool, which means you can see the fruit flies.
名前はスチールウール、ショウジョウバエが見えるという意味です。
If you have seen fruit flies
ショウジョウバエを見たことがある方は
There are a lot of these thin ones on its back
背中にはこんな細いのがたくさんある
Then the steel wool is actually a sensory organ of the nerves.
スチールウールは実際には神経の感覚器官です。
under it there is a hair growing on the outside
その下には外側に毛が生えています
it has a nerve cell underneath it
その下に神経細胞がある
So when you touch this it's outside this hair
だからあなたがこれに触れると、それはこの髪の毛の外側にあります
The nerve cells underneath it will have a feeling
その下の神経細胞は感覚を持っています
This signal is then sent to the state-run central nervous system
この信号はその後、国家が運営する中枢神経系に送信されます。
That's why the state-owned company knows that someone touches it like this
だからこそ、国営企業は誰かがこのように触ったことを知っているのです
In fact, there are a lot of people in the state camp
実際、州キャンプにはたくさんの人がいます
you can see a lot of roots
根がたくさん見えます
And it's very neatly arranged
そしてとても綺麗に並べられています
Then there are some gaps in the middle like this
するとこのように真ん中に隙間ができてしまいます
This is a state run one
これは州が運営するものです
Then when I was doing postdoctoral research at the time
当時私がポスドクの研究をしていたとき
while in san francisco
サンフランシスコにいる間に
In fact, the research is such a simple question that
実際、この研究は非常に単純な質問です。
How did this steel wool come about?
このスチールウールはどのようにして生まれたのでしょうか？
In fact, after years of research, a researcher found that
実際、何年にもわたる研究の後、ある研究者は次のことを発見しました。
In fact, the simple thing is that fate is destiny
実際、単純なことは、運命は運命だということです
That is to say, these steel wool
つまりこのスチールウールは
What kind of nerve organelles grow under it
その下にはどのような神経小器官が成長しているのか
It was doomed when it was born
生まれたときから運命づけられていた
Then we can see that
そうすれば、それがわかります
One advantage of using Guina for research is that
研究にギナを使用する利点の 1 つは次のとおりです。
We can mutate a gene
遺伝子を突然変異させることができる
So we call a gene a proneural gene
したがって、遺伝子をプロニューラル遺伝子と呼びます
It is a gene related to the formation of nerve cells
神経細胞の形成に関わる遺伝子です
When it can be removed, you saw that it was on the back of the fruit camp
剥がせるとフルーツキャンプの裏側にあったことが分かりました
It was supposed to grow a lot of steel wool
スチールウールが大量に生えるはずだった
Actually gone
実際に行ってしまった
It's just a few skin cells left like this
このように皮膚細胞が少しだけ残っているだけです
just a skin cell
ただの皮膚細胞
So let's talk about gene expression
それでは遺伝子発現について話しましょう
it can form this steel wool
このスチールウールを形成することができます
Then it can grow the nerve cells of its sensory organs
その後、感覚器官の神経細胞を成長させることができます
Then you can let it feel these external stimuli
次に、これらの外部刺激を感じさせることができます
Then there are some responses like this
すると、このような反応がいくつかあります
So this proneural gene
つまり、このプロニューラル遺伝子は
Actually when I come back
実は帰ってきたら
It is also the beginning of research on this subject
これはこのテーマに関する研究の始まりでもあります
That is, how do proneural genes work?
つまり、プロニューラル遺伝子はどのように機能するのでしょうか?
Well, of course there is not only one kind of fruit camp.
さて、もちろんフルーツキャンプは1種類だけではありません。
sensory nerve cells
感覚神経細胞
Our fruit camp is relatively simple
私たちのフルーツキャンプは比較的シンプルです
So we can in its peripheral nervous system
その末梢神経系でできること
see that there are three different types of nerve cells
3つの異なる種類の神経細胞があることがわかります
a type of nerve cell called the extrinsic
外因性神経細胞と呼ばれる神経細胞の一種
organ , we just saw that steel hair
オルガン、私たちはその鋼の髪を見たばかりです
it can feel the touch
それは感触を感じることができます
Under the table, we just can't see under the table
テーブルの下では、テーブルの下は見えません
In fact there is another sense organ
実は別の感覚器官がある
It's actually feeling the contraction of the muscles
実際に筋肉の収縮を感じます
or can make it feel balanced
またはバランスが取れていると感じさせることができます
it looks very different
とても違って見えます
You can see it looks very different than this one
これとはかなり異なって見えることがわかります
Another type of neuron called a multivelocity synapse
多速度シナプスと呼ばれる別のタイプのニューロン
It's very long and fast
とても長くて速いです
it also has its function
それはその機能もあります
they look very different
彼らはとても違って見えます
They also function very differently
機能も大きく異なります
But how different are they?
しかし、それらはどれくらい違うのでしょうか？
The teacher is when they decide to say
先生は彼らが言うことを決めるときです
are they different
違うのですか
The question we're asking is that
私たちが尋ねているのは、
How did this nerve cell become different?
この神経細胞はどのように変わったのでしょうか?
that's when it decided it was different
それは違うと判断したときです
This is consistent with our research findings
これは私たちの研究結果と一致しています
very imaginative very different
非常に想像力に富む、非常に異なる
It turns out that very, very early in embryonic development, very early
胚発生の非常に早い段階、非常に早い段階で
At the beginning, it was an epidermal cell formed from outside
初めは外側から形成された表皮細胞でした
He already decided his fate
彼はすでに運命を決めている
In other words, the proneural gene we just talked about
言い換えれば、今話したプロニューラル遺伝子
He may have been out very early when he was paired to express a proneural gene
彼は、プロニューラル遺伝子を発現するためにペアになったとき、非常に早い段階で外出していたのかもしれない
He decided to become this sensory organ
彼は自分がこの感覚器官になると決めた
But if another proneural gene is expressed
しかし、別のプロニューラル遺伝子が発現すると、
when it's called etonal
それがエトーナルと呼ばれるとき
He might have influenced him to change into another form.
彼の影響で別の姿に変化したのかもしれない。
the last amus
最後一個amus
He may also mean that when he expresses
彼が表現するとき、それは次のことを意味しているのかもしれません
He formed this kind of nerve cells
彼はこの種の神経細胞を形成しました
So it echoes what I just said at the beginning
つまり、私が冒頭で言ったことと同じです
Although his nerve cells look very different
彼の神経細胞はかなり異なって見えますが、
very different functions
非常に異なる機能
But he seems to be at the beginning of his birth
しかし彼はまだ誕生の初期にいるようだ
His expression of nerve genes has already determined that he becomes a nerve cell
彼の神経遺伝子の発現により、彼が神経細胞になることがすでに決定されています
Then this is a lot like destiny
それならこれは運命によく似ています
It was doomed early in the morning
早朝に駄目だった
He will be able to escape the arrangement of fate
彼は運命の定めから逃れることができるだろう
cell fate decisions
細胞運命の決定
Well, this state-run research is actually in this area
さて、この国営研究は実際にはこの分野にあります
great contribution
大きな貢献
Because these protothec
なぜならこれらのプロトセックは
not only in the state
州内だけでなく
In fact, his evolution has a very high degree of reservation
実際、彼の進化には非常に高い懸念があり、
So a lot of it is found in mice
そのため、その多くはマウスに含まれています
Protothecium gene
プロトテシウム遺伝子
Then we know rats are more complicated than state run
そうすれば、rat は国家運営よりも複雑であることがわかります
He has all sorts of peripheral germ cells
彼はあらゆる種類の末梢生殖細胞を持っています
Then they express different protothecium genes
次に、異なるプロトセシウム遺伝子を発現します。
in different places
さまざまな場所で
that can decide him
それが彼を決めることができる
Where will you be in the future
将来どこにいますか
Grow this different germ cells out
この異なる生殖細胞を成長させてください
So this looks like a
これは次のようになります
very simple law
とても単純な法律
that is, gene expression
つまり遺伝子発現
and very early expression
そして非常に初期の表現
can determine the germ cell
生殖細胞を決定できる
The fate of this future is like this
この未来の運命はこうなる
this is a
これは
pretty simple example
かなり単純な例
That
それか
But
しかし
seems to be a gene expression
遺伝子の発現だと思われる
It seems that the decision can be made immediately
すぐに決断できそうです
He's going to turn into a germ cell
彼は生殖細胞に変わってしまうだろう
But it's actually that simple
しかし、実際はとても簡単です
That in the study found that
研究でわかったことは、
It's not that simple
そんなに単純じゃないよ
Discovered that you are going to become a germ cell
自分が生殖細胞になることを発見
You go through a so-called competitive process
いわゆる競争プロセスを経る
That's what I said in it
その中でそう言ってた
There is also a process of competition between cells
細胞間の競争のプロセスもあります
Then we know that in some epidermis
すると、表皮の一部では
So the surface layer of cells
つまり細胞の表層は
For example, here are 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
たとえば、1 2 3 4 5 6 7 です。
7 cells
7セル
Then there is only one of these 7 cells
そうすると、これら 7 つのセルのうち 1 つだけが存在します。
7 will only choose one
7は1つだけを選択します
to become a nerve cell
神経細胞になる
Come on, that sounds full
さあ、いっぱいですね
highly competitive
競争力がある
It's better than the election we just ended
終わったばかりの選挙よりは良いよ
more intense feeling
より激しい感情
7 only one
7 たった一つだけ
Then who and how to choose
では、誰をどのように選ぶか
how to compete
どのように競争するか
Then we often want to say that competition has two strategies
次に、競争には 2 つの戦略があると言いたいことがよくあります。
you would think right
あなたは正しく考えるでしょう
how is one
一人はどうですか
self-improvement, right?
自己改善ですよね？
I make myself better
私は自分自身をより良くします
I beat others, right?
私は他の人を倒しましたよね？
Others got 99 points, I got 100 points
他の人は99点、私は100点
i beat him
私は彼を倒しました
What's another strategy for the competition?
競争のための別の戦略は何ですか?
Yes, like an election
そう、選挙みたいに
Initiation marks, right?
イニシエーションマークですよね？
make others worse
他人を悪くする
Then this competition is actually more practical than a bad strategy
そうなると、この競争は実際には下手な戦略よりも実践的なものになる
We call it the test of will
私たちはそれを意志のテストと呼んでいます
test will
意志をテストする
That is to say
つまり
If one of the cells wants to become that nerve cell
細胞の1つがその神経細胞になりたい場合
it sends out a signal
それは信号を送ります
go to the cells next to the consciousness say
意識の隣の細胞に行って言う
Don't be like me, don't be like a nerve cell
私のようにならないでください、神経細胞のようにならないでください
ok like this i mean
さて、このように、つまり
It's just that I'm a volition, you don't want
それは私が意志を持っているだけです、あなたは望んでいません
don't be like me
私のようにならないでください
OK, there is a premise here, that is
OK、ここには前提があります。
In fact, each of these cells has the potential to become
実際、これらの細胞のそれぞれは次のような可能性を持っています。
The ability of nerve cells
神経細胞の能力
i have the potential
私には可能性があります
can become nerve cells
神経細胞になることができる
But because of competition
でも競争があるから
Only one can become a nerve cell
神経細胞になれるのは1つだけ
Then the rest will retreat back into an epidermal cell
その後、残りは表皮細胞に戻ります
OK
OK
How to do this experiment
この実験のやり方
Let's say this is the final conclusion
これが最終的な結論だとしましょう
How about this experiment
この実験はどうでしょうか
Well, there is actually a very simple experiment that
実は、とても簡単な実験があります。
Someone went to observe the embryo and said
誰かが胎児を観察しに行ってこう言いました。
Here's a group of cells, and one of them
これは細胞のグループとそのうちの 1 つです
seems to start turning into something like a nerve cell
神経細胞のようなものに変化し始めているようだ
start to change
変わり始める
I'll take a laser then
それではレーザーを撮ります
Strong laser kills this one
強力なレーザーでこれを殺す
what happened then?
それで何が起こったのですか？
If this one is going to become a nerve cell and be killed
こいつが神経細胞になって殺されるなら
What will happen to the other six?
残りの6人はどうなるのでしょうか？
Clam?
蛤?
replace, who replaces?
代わります、誰が代わりますか？
re-compete
再競争する
you might just say
あなたはただ言うかもしれません
we put that
私たちはそれを置きます
It seems that the person who is going to be elected will be grinded and killed.
当選する人は粉砕されて殺されるらしい。
There are six other people to compete, right?
他に6人が出場するんですよね？
How many people will become nerve cells?
何人が神経細胞になるでしょうか？
still one
まだ一つ
So why is he still one?
では、なぜ彼はまだ1人なのでしょうか？
six in six
6分の6
the answer is one
答えは一つです
It's simple to say
言うのは簡単です
Because these six, these seven cells
なぜなら、この 6 つ、この 7 つの細胞が
His ability, has the potential to become a nerve cell
彼の能力は神経細胞になる可能性を秘めている
He also has the potential to suppress others
他人を抑圧する可能性も秘めている
So when we kill this
それでこれを殺すと
One of the others becomes a nerve cell
残りの1つは神経細胞になります
He also wants to restrain others
彼も他人を拘束したい
I was in class at that time
その時私は授業中だった
when telling jokes
冗談を言うとき
I often think of the former Yiqingzhuang case in Taiwan
私はよく台湾のかつてのイーチン荘事件を思い出します。
We often arrest gangsters, don't we?
よく暴力団員を逮捕しますよね。
It turns out that strategy doesn't work
戦略が機能していないことが判明した
Because how about you arrest big brother
だって兄貴を逮捕したらどうですか？
Brothers will compete, right?
兄弟で競争するんですよね？
Then someone became a big brother
そしたら誰かがお兄さんになった
So this is very troublesome
だからこれはとても面倒なんです
And what must the elder brother do?
そして兄は何をしなければなりませんか？
Because he wants to help other boys, right?
彼は他の男の子を助けたいからですよね？
So here's an experiment that's actually quite interesting
ここで実際に非常に興味深い実験を紹介します
That is to say, he has a will
つまり彼には意志がある
Cells compete by suppressing others
細胞は他の細胞を抑制することで競争する
Then this example is a very interesting example
それでは、この例は非常に興味深い例です
Then we see that lateral will
すると、横方向の意志がわかります。
is this a fair competition
これは公正な競争ですか
In fact, our scientists found in the research that
実際、私たちの科学者たちは研究で次のことを発見しました。
When this side will will produce a
こちら側がいつ生産するか
on the surface of this cell through two proteins
2つのタンパク質を介してこの細胞の表面に
exchange of
的交換
It sends the signal that you can't be like a neuron
ニューロンのようにはなれないという信号を送る
So there is a saying that proves that this is a gene related to side shifting characters
これが横移動文字に関連する遺伝子であることを証明する格言があります
That is to say, you mutate this protein
つまり、このタンパク質を変異させます。
Let it mutate, make it impossible to pass the signal
変異させて信号を通せなくする
At this time, it is different from the experimental results just now.
この時点では先ほどの実験結果とは異なります。
how is it
どうですか
Because I said each one has the potential to become a nerve cell
それぞれが神経細胞になる可能性を持っていると言いましたから
So after you cancel the side shifting word
したがって、横に移動する単語をキャンセルした後、
They have no communication, no competition
彼らにはコミュニケーションも競争力もありません
So each of them has become a nerve cell.
つまり、それぞれが神経細胞になったのです。
that's cool
それは良いアイデアです
So this is a process of shifting characters sideways
これは文字を横にずらす処理です
Everyone has to compete with each other and you can suppress others
誰もが互いに競争する必要があり、他の人を抑制することもできます
Then I now use the genetic method to remove the suppression mechanism
次に、遺伝的手法を使用して抑制メカニズムを除去します。
Everyone becomes this nerve cell
誰もがこの神経細胞になる
Is there any evidence for this?
これに関する証拠はありますか?
Then I will show you a picture and everyone will know
それから写真を見せます、そして誰もが知っています
see this one
これを見てください
When we said this was normal
これが普通だと言ったら
this one gang
このギャング
Next to it are actually epidermal cells
その隣には実は表皮細胞があります
very many epidermal cells
非常に多くの表皮細胞
Then you saw that I removed the mechanism of this one
それから私がこの機構を取り除いたのがわかりました
Wow, this is one weight and one weight this
うわー、これは 1 つの重さ、これは 1 つの重さです
Steel wool, there are divine sound cells underneath
スチールウール、その下には神聖なサウンドセルがある
Shenyin cells
神陰細胞
So this means that we put this mechanism
つまり、このメカニズムを導入したということになります
to remove later
後で削除する
then this this this
それからこれこれこれ
Everyone will become Shenyin cells
誰もが神陰細胞になる
This is how everyone chooses
みんなそうやって選ぶんだよ
not bad
悪くない
That
それか
Then here's another interesting question.
それから、もう一つ興味深い質問があります。
this
これ
I often say this example in class
この例を授業でよく言います
That is to say, once the cell has a cell
つまり、細胞が細胞を持つと、
I just talked about this cell
先ほどこの細胞について話しました
it is in
それは中にあります
During the competition just now
たった今大会中
has been selected
選択されました
So in the future you will become like a Shenyin cell
だから将来あなたは神陰細胞のようになるでしょう
Then does it really become a Shenyin cell?
では、本当に神陰細胞になるのでしょうか？
we later found out that
私たちは後でそれを知りました
Hey, this process is actually quite laborious.
いや、このプロセスは実はかなり手間がかかるんです。
it doesn't mean i'm in this
私がこの中にいるという意味ではありません
Among seven or eight people, I chose
7、8人の中から私が選んだのは、
I will become a divine sound cell
神のサウンドセルになるよ
In fact, there is still a process in the middle
実はまだ途中の工程があるんです
This is really going to become a Shenyin cell.
これが本当に神陰細胞になります。
It's a very hard process, this is a hard process with thousands of mountains and rivers
それは非常に困難なプロセスです、これは何千もの山と川を伴う困難なプロセスです
What about this cell, it divides
この細胞はどうでしょうか、分裂します
become two cells, and those two cells are dividing to become two cells
2つの細胞になり、その2つの細胞が分裂して2つの細胞になります
This is dividing into two cells like this
こんな感じで2つの細胞に分かれています
In fact, these four cells will form the structure of the anal hair we just talked about.
実際、これら 4 つの細胞は、先ほど話した肛門毛の構造を形成します。
So the anal hair itself is composed of four cells
つまり、肛門毛自体は4つの細胞で構成されています
Then it's actually a cell that just competed for the battalion after it splits
それは実際には、分裂した後に大隊を争ったばかりの細胞です
become four cells, then the composition of these four cells becomes a thin and wide
4つのセルになると、この4つのセルの構成は薄くて広いものになります
So this one feels pretty simple and we like doing pattern research with this
これは非常にシンプルに感じられるので、これを使ってパターン調査を行うのが好きです
because it's so simple, four cells
とてもシンプルなので、4つのセル
But there is a big problem here
しかしここで大きな問題が発生します
the big problem is that
大きな問題はそれです
These four cells are different
これら 4 つの細胞は異なります
There is a cell that is responsible for growing the outer hair
外側の毛を成長させる細胞がある
Then there is a cell, which is supporting the structure of the hair
次に、髪の構造をサポートする細胞があります。
this orange cell
このオレンジ色のセル
The structure that supports it is tilted up like this
それを支える構造物はこんな感じで上に傾いています
There's a nerve cell down there
その下に神経細胞がある
green this is a nerve cell
緑色、これは神経細胞です
it wants to connect
それはつながりたい
Its speed will connect to the muscles of the anal hairs
そのスピードは肛門の毛の筋肉に繋がる
it can feel when the anal hairs move
肛門の毛が動くと感じることができる
it has a signal to pass on
伝えるべき信号がある
Next to this nerve cell is another cell that protects it
この神経細胞の隣には、それを保護する別の細胞があります
so you see 1234
1234 がわかります
that question
その質問
As far as we were studying cell division
私たちが細胞分裂を研究している限りでは
Maybe everyone has studied biology in high school
おそらく誰もが高校で生物学を勉強したことがあると思います
One cell becomes two cells
1 つのセルが 2 つのセルになります
Those two cells
その2つの細胞
will it be different
違うでしょうか
we learned to say
私たちはこう言うことを学びました
A cell divides to become two different cells
細胞が分裂して 2 つの異なる細胞になる
Then what we all read in the textbooks
それでは、私たちが教科書で読んだことは
Almost one cell becomes two cells
ほぼ 1 つのセルが 2 つのセルになります
Two cells and then four cells
2 つのセル、次に 4 つのセル
The cells look exactly the same
細胞は全く同じに見えます
but we know
でも私たちは知っています
What we have grown into today
今日私たちが成長したもの
When we have so many different cells in our body
私たちの体内には非常に多くの異なる細胞があるので、
Cells must become different during this process
このプロセス中に細胞は異なるものになるはずです
right
右
how to be different
どのように違うのか
Then here is a very good example that says
次に、これが非常に良い例です。
its split in the middle
真ん中で分かれています
After splitting, or when splitting, you already know that you are going to be different
別れた後、または別れたとき、あなたはすでに自分が違うものになることを知っています
One cell becomes two cells, two cells are different
1 つのセルが 2 つのセルになり、2 つのセルは異なります
Well, how to achieve this? I let one cell divide and the two cells become different
では、これを実現するにはどうすればよいでしょうか? 1 つの細胞を分裂させ、2 つの細胞を異なるものにします。
It's an interesting subject
興味深い話題ですね
Then I will show you this, and you can take a look at the next one here
それでは、これをお見せします。次はここで見てください。
In fact, this is a bit like this, and it's also a bit like this
実は、これも少し似ていますし、これも少し似ています
We can think of it as a concept of property
それを財産の概念として考えることができます
When a parent distributes this property to two children, it can actually be divided differently
親がこのプロパティを 2 人の子に分配する場合、実際には異なる分割方法が可能です
So we see that when the cell is about to divide
つまり、細胞が分裂しようとしているときがわかります。
You see it's his, we say mitosis, spin down
あなたはそれが彼のものであることがわかります、私たちは有糸分裂、スピンダウンと言います
It's on the left and the right, you see the left and the right, this dyed protein is red
左と右です、左と右が見えます、この染色されたタンパク質は赤いです
This dyed protein is green
この染色されたタンパク質は緑色です
The two are not the same, assigned to different proteins
この 2 つは同じではなく、異なるタンパク質に割り当てられています
So cells divide, so you see this side, right this movie
細胞が分裂するので、ここにこれが表示されます、この映画です
There are people in it that say, look, red and green
その中には、ほら、赤と緑って言う人がいます
Green goes to one cell, red stays in another cell
緑はあるセルに移動し、赤は別のセルに留まります
So this cell division actually seems to be
つまり、この細胞分裂は実際には次のようです
I can assign different
異なるものを割り当てることができます
Properties assign different proteins to two different purple cells
プロパティは、2 つの異なる紫色のセルに異なるタンパク質を割り当てます。
and if your eyes
そしてもしあなたの目が
With a little effort, you can also notice that
少し努力すれば、次のことに気づくこともできます
This cell is relatively small, this cell is relatively large, right?
このセルは比較的小さく、このセルは比較的大きいですよね?
So our distribution can be divided and uneven
したがって、私たちの分布は分割され、不均一になる可能性があります
unequal like this to split like this
このように不平等になると、このように分割されます
so
それで
We can imagine that just now
私たちは今それを想像することができます
won
勝利した
After testing is
テスト後は
came out and won that cell
出てきて独房を勝ち取った
The two cells can become different when it divides
2 つの細胞は分裂すると異なるものになる可能性があります
Because the assigned things are different
与えられたものが違うから
Then this cell is different when it divides
そうすると、この細胞は分裂すると違うのです
This is not the same, which can constitute four different
これは同じではなく、4 つの異なるものを構成する可能性があります。
For purple cells, four cells are enough
紫色のセルの場合は 4 つのセルで十分です
combined into one
一つに結合された
sensory organs like this
このような感覚器官
Well, there is experimental evidence for this, for example,
そうですね、これには実験的証拠があります。たとえば、
we have some mutants
私たちにはいくつかのミュータントがいます
that this
これは
just won that cell if
もしそのセルに勝てば
split did not take place
分割は行われませんでした
One of these proteins is missing the red green protein
これらのタンパク質の 1 つは、赤緑色のタンパク質を欠いています。
You will find that it divides and produces two identical purple cells
分裂して 2 つの同じ紫色の細胞が生成されることがわかります。
It's not doing the so-called asymmetric cell division at this time
現時点では、いわゆる非対称細胞分裂は行っていません。
Then when the cell divides again, there will be two identical cells again.
その後、細胞が再び分裂すると、再び 2 つの同一の細胞が存在します。
So this produces four cells that are exactly the same red
したがって、これにより、まったく同じ赤色の 4 つのセルが生成されます。
Then in another mutant we saw that
次に、別の突然変異体で次のことがわかりました。
produced four nerve cells
4つの神経細胞が生成されました
Those horse babies outside are gone.
外にいる馬の赤ちゃんはいなくなってしまった。
so tell us here
だからここで教えてください
There seems to be something quite unfair here
ここにはかなり不公平な点があるようです
That is to say, when the cells divide, the substances that everyone distributes
つまり、細胞が分裂するとき、全員が物質を分配します
So this includes protein or RNA
つまり、これにはタンパク質またはRNAが含まれます
Everyone is allocated different amounts
全員に異なる金額が割り当てられます
So this cell inherits something different
つまり、この細胞は何か異なるものを受け継いでいます
Of course, the direction of its subsequent development will be different.
もちろん、その後の発展の方向性は異なります。
become different cells
別の細胞になる
OK
OK
No problem at all
全く問題なし
Then what I tell you now is very
それでは、私が今あなたに言うことは非常に重要です
the feeling of something very unfair
何かとても不公平な気がする
who was born that gene
その遺伝子を生み出したのは誰ですか
What protein to express inherits the expression at the beginning
どのタンパク質を発現させるかは最初の発現を継承する
proneuroelastin
プロニューロエラスチン
Then go through this fierce competition
そして、この熾烈な競争を乗り越えてください
And then finally distributed unequal
そして最終的には不平等に分配される
And then there is only one cell at the end
そして最後にはセルが 1 つだけあります
win out into nerve cells
神経細胞を勝ち取る
Then everything else becomes like this non-nerve cell
そうなると、他のすべてはこの非神経細胞のようになる
That's the fact that we're
それが私たちがいるという事実です
But now it's the reverse example
しかし今は逆の例です
That is to say, in the whole developmental process
つまり、発達過程全体において、
Sometimes we see cells that actually cooperate
時々、実際に協力している細胞が見られます
cooperate with each other
互いに協力し合う
then hand in hand then together
それから手をつないで、そして一緒に
to line up and then to make this last
並んで、そしてこれを最後にするために
A developmental process looks like this
開発プロセスはこんな感じ
And they also have some so-called altruistic behaviors
そして、いわゆる利他的な行動もあります
it means i would rather sacrifice myself
それはむしろ自分を犠牲にしたほうが良いという意味です
Dedicated to this society
この社会に捧げます
So the other side of the example we are looking at now is that
したがって、今見ている例の反対側は次のとおりです。
a wonderful society
素晴らしい社会
what does cell society look like
細胞社会はどのようなものですか
Then this is from this
それではこれからです
Deputy Speech of State Operations
国家運営副演説
You may have seen a lot of state-run assistant actors.
国営の助役をたくさん見たことがあるかもしれません。
this is very neat
これはとても素敵です
Then this state-run deputy actor is different from our human eyes
それでは、この国営の副俳優は私たちの人間の目とは異なります
Small eyes make up 800
小さな目は800を構成します
small eyes
小さな目
very neatly arranged
とてもきれいに整理されている
then i will always be in
そうすれば私はいつもそこにいるよ
ask students to say
生徒たちに言わせる
how do you use when things are neatly arranged
物事がきちんと整理されているときに何を使いますか
How to make it line up very neatly
とても綺麗に並べる方法
the first one is to say
最初のものは言うことです
Because we used to live in the dormitory of the central courtyard
私たちは中庭の寮に住んでいたので
often hear this
これはよく聞きます
When Hu Shiguo offered small favors
胡世国がささやかな好意を寄せたとき
Some people say it's on par
同等だという人もいる
Then all students will
そうすれば生徒全員が
align in the image and arrange
画像に合わせて配置する
So one possibility is how
それで、1つの可能性は次のとおりです
Everyone is here, line up
みんなここにいるよ、並んでね
Finally a signal came, everyone said
ついに信号が来た、と皆が言った
Everyone look up, everyone look up, right?
みんな上を向いて、みんな上を向いてね？
This is a way to arrange
アレンジ方法です
that another
それは別の
Of course, some people will be more clear that is to say
もちろん、もっと明確に言う人もいるでしょう。
like a crystalline way
まるで水晶のように
We know that crystallization often has a seed crystal
結晶化には種結晶が存在することが多いことがわかっています。
Then there may be a first stroke from the middle
その後、真ん中から最初のストロークがあるかもしれません
then slowly
それからゆっくりと
Slowly stack up one by one
一つ一つゆっくりと積み上げていきます
Then we can fold very neatly
そうすればとてもきれいに折りたたむことができます
like the process of crystallization
結晶化の過程のように
It can be arranged one by one
1つずつアレンジ可能です
Then we can imagine
それから私たちは想像することができます
there may be two ways
考えられる方法は2つあります
can make this sure eye
この確かな目を作ることができます
The recovery is very neatly arranged like this
リカバリーはこのように非常にきれいに配置されています
Our experiment is to say that
私たちの実験で言えることは、
There may be a third way
第三の道もあるかもしれない
This eye developed from this piece
この目はこの作品から生まれました
After development, you see this area becomes like this
開発後、このエリアは次のようになります
you can see say
言うことがわかります
You can imagine that this row of cells
このセルの行が次のようになっていると想像できます。
express a very specific gene like this
このように非常に特異的な遺伝子を発現します
we found that
私たちはそれを見つけました
can't do this
これはできません
According to the research findings of many people
多くの人の研究結果によると
This process is actually not the two ways we mentioned earlier.
このプロセスは実際には、前述した 2 つの方法ではありません。
But the third way is to say
しかし、3番目の方法はこう言うことです
One way you can do that is
それを行うための 1 つの方法は、
Can be arranged in a row-by-row manner
行ごとに配置可能
Then we see this row means that
次に、この行が意味することがわかります。
The development of this eye is not actually a start
この目の発達は実際には始まりではありません
Then everyone holidays way
それからみんな休日を過ごしましょう
not all together
全員一緒ではない
And above is row by row
そして上は行ごとです
Then this looks like everyone went to the beach to watch the waves
それから、これはみんなが波を見るためにビーチに行ったようです
float over like this
このように浮かんでいます
a slope like this
こんな坂道
so it starts from here
ここから始まります
Wave by wave, wave by wave
一波過去,一個波一個波過去
Then everyone will line up
そしたらみんな並びますよ
How to arrange this? Actually
これをどうやってアレンジすればいいのでしょうか？
The theory we put forward is that
私たちが提唱する理論は、
As long as you have one row, the previous row is neat
1 行あれば、前の行はきれいになります
Suppose we could say something like
次のようなことが言えるとします。
If everyone is in order in this row
この列に全員が整列していれば
As for the people in the next row, just follow
隣の列の人はフォローしてください
Just wipe the gap between the two people in the front row
最前列の二人の間を拭くだけ
so you know what i mean
だから私が言いたいことはわかるでしょう
I say what the next row will show up
次の行に何が表示されるかを言う
The next row is arranged first, how about the second row?
次の行が先に配置されていますが、2行目はどうでしょうか？
Just wipe the gap between the two people in front of the first row
1列目の前の2人の間の隙間を拭くだけ
So we see that there seems to be this smell here
ここにこの匂いがあるようです
You see that this row of cells
このセルの行がわかります。
Then the next row of cells
次に、次のセル行
It seems that the cells are spaced in the middle
セルが真ん中に間隔を置いて配置されているように見えます
So what we say is
そこで私たちが言うことは、
As long as the first row of cells is neat
前の行のセルがきれいである限り
Then the next row is neatly looking at the gaps of the previous row and rubbing in.
そして次の列が前の列の隙間を綺麗に見て擦り込んでいきます。
Then it can be neatly followed, right?
そうすればきちんと従うことができますよね？
Row after row can be very neat like this
このように行ごとに非常にきれいに配置できます
So it's a simple idea
だからそれは単純なアイデアです
There is a problem here, how to form the first row
ここで問題が発生します。最初の行をどのように形成するかです。
How do you have the neatness in the first row
どうしたら1列目の整頓ができますか？
In fact, we can see this
実際、これを見ることができます
This is what I imagined
これが私が想像したものです
No, not necessarily experimentally verified
いいえ、必ずしも実験的に検証されているわけではありません
You just said it looked like this
ちょうどこんな感じだと言いましたね
Then you only need one in the first row
そうすれば、最初の行に 1 つだけ必要になります
Then one of course is very neat with itself
もちろん、それ自体は非常にきちんとしています
For the second row, there are two, right?
2列目は2つですよね？
It's far behind him, there are only three in the third row
彼の後ろは遠い、3列目には3人しかいない
Then get away from those two
だったらその二人から離れろよ
In addition to saying, we can imagine saying
言うことに加えて、次のように言うことも想像できます。
As long as one row is neat, the next row will be uneven
ある列がきれいであれば、次の列は不均一になります
just follow neatly
ただきちんと従ってください
Like a wave of cell division
細胞分裂の波のように
that goes all the way from the back to the front
それは後ろから前までずっと続いています
Then it can be worth this at the beginning
そうすれば、最初はこれで価値があるかもしれません
Roughly arranged in the way
ざっくりとやり方を整理すると
Then everyone can have a neat one
そうすれば誰もがきちんとしたものを手に入れることができます
Arranged like this
このように配置すると
OK
OK
this is
これは
Of course, this has not been confirmed in many places.
もちろん、これは多くの場所で確認されていません。
But this is an interesting idea like this
でもこういう発想は面白いですね
There are still some in this process
まだこの過程にあるものもあります
movement of cell populations
細胞集団の移動
I find this very interesting
これはとても興味深いと思います
If you watch this sub-act
このサブアクトを視聴すると
This is the sub-actor and this is sliced
これはサブアクターで、これはスライスされています
You slice him sideways like this
このように彼を横にスライスします
sliced ​​like this
こんな感じでスライスしました
inside the slice if you look at it with one of the eyes
片目で見るとスライスの内側
you see it becomes like this
こうなるのがわかりますか
This is the photoreceptor cell
これが光受容細胞です
it has a
それは
An arrangement of P-type
P型のアレンジメント
P type arrangement
P型配列
you all look carefully
皆さんよく見てください
when you look at this one
これを見ると
Do you feel that other places are different
他の場所は違うと思いますか
yes someone saw it
はい、誰かが見ました
up and down are mirror images
上下は鏡像です
So the T-shape above looks like this
上のT字型は次のようになります
The following T shape looks like this
以下のT字型はこんな感じ
The sharper places are this one facing down and this one facing up
鋭利な場所は、ここが下を向いており、ここが上を向いています
How did this come about?
これはどのようにして起こったのでしょうか?
Because we just said that its differentiation process is from behind
なぜなら、差別化プロセスは後ろからであると述べたばかりだからです。
keep going forward row by row
一行ずつ前進し続ける
Then there seems to be a line somewhere in the middle
すると真ん中に線があるように見えます
separate it
分けて
up and down this
この上下に
This group of cells will do different exercises
この細胞グループはさまざまな運動を行います
Therefore, in the research here, many people have found that
したがって、ここでの研究で多くの人が次のことを発見しました。
In fact, there is actually a group of cells together
実際には、実際には細胞のグループが集まっています
a process of rotation
回転の過程
We see that the above cells are rotating clockwise
上のセルが時計回りに回転していることがわかります。
The cells below are rotating counterclockwise
下のセルは反時計回りに回転しています
So we can form up and down this
それで、これを上下に形成できます
There is an arrangement of mirror images like this
このような鏡像の配置があります
So the formation of this ghost silver eye it neatly lined up
だからこのゴーストシルバーアイのフォーメーションが綺麗に並んだんだ
In fact, this process is quite a lot
実際、このプロセスは非常に手間がかかります
Now let's talk about the third process
さて、3番目のプロセスについて話しましょう
The fourth process is actually
4番目のプロセスは実際には
Quite a special process of standing and collapsing
立ったり倒れたりするかなり特殊なプロセス
that is
あれは
Finally, to form a very neat monocular
最後に、非常にきれいな単眼鏡を形成します。
Each single eye should be very neat and fixed.
それぞれの目は非常にきちんとしていて、しっかりと固定されている必要があります。
In the end, a very good structure can be formed
最終的には非常に優れた構造が形成される
But in the process of development
しかし開発の途中で
Often a strategy is to say
戦略としてよく言われるのは、
Your whole eye has 800 small eyes
あなたの目には800個の小さな目があります
If each small-eyed character has 20 cells
小さな目のキャラクターが 20 個のマス目を持つ場合
how many cells do you need
細胞は何個必要ですか
800 times 20
800×20
right
右
This is 16000 cells
これは16000セルです
That's how many times it takes for a cell to divide
細胞が分裂するのにかかる回数です
will reach 16,000 cells
16,000セルに達します
Then cell division can be controlled so precisely
そうすれば、細胞分裂を非常に正確に制御できるようになります
Generated exactly 16,000 cells
正確に 16,000 個のセルが生成されました
actually not
実際にはそうではありません
So the development strategy is often
したがって、開発戦略は多くの場合、
We often see a developmental strategy that says
次のような開発戦略をよく目にします。
We'd rather do more first
むしろ最初にもっとや​​るべきだ
Let's make 20,000 cells
細胞を2万個作ってみよう
18000 cells are good
18000セルは良いです
we would rather have more
むしろもっと欲しいです
but not less
でもそれ以下ではない
that's a little more
それはもう少しです
but more is good
しかし、それ以上は良いことです
but there will be problems
しかし問題もあるだろう
For example, we see
たとえば、次のようになります。
during development
開発中
24 hours
24時間
The arrangement is not neat
アレンジがきちんとしていない
Especially the outermost circle
特に一番外側の円
There seem to be many more cells
他にも細胞がたくさんあるようです
and then 24 hours later
そして24時間後
neatly arranged
きれいに整えられた
In fact, there is a cell in the middle
実は真ん中に細胞があります
The process of the wither
枯れるまでの過程
That is to say, it is ugly
つまり醜いんです
If there are too many cells, they will die.
細胞が多すぎると細胞は死んでしまいます。
just die
ただ死ぬだけ
So in fact some cells in the middle
実際、中央にあるいくつかのセル
a signal appears
信号が現れる
There is a signal in the middle
真ん中に信号があります
Then put the next cell
次に、次のセルを入れます
let it do this withering
これを枯れさせましょう
So this cell
それでこの細胞は
Just the right number will be left
ちょうどいい数字が残る
Then form a grid of gold grids like this
次に、このように金のグリッドのグリッドを形成します
Then we can see that
そうすれば、それがわかります
If the withering network of the cell is
細胞の萎縮ネットワークが
when it didn't happen
それが起こらなかったとき
In fact, the eyes began to appear some
実際、目が少し見え始めました
The messy phenomenon is like this
めちゃくちゃ現象はこんな感じ
or hypercellularity
または細胞過多
or irregular arrangement
または不規則な配置
So this we can say
だからこれは言える
It's an act of setting it up
それを設定する行為です
some cells during development
発生中のいくつかの細胞
when its function has ended
その機能が終わったとき
or when it is not needed
またはそれが必要でないとき
Or just after the temporary function ends
または一時的な機能が終了した直後
then it is possible to carry out the withering of cells
その後、細胞を枯らすことが可能になります
Then just for the sake of this perfect state of the whole society
そして、社会全体がこの完璧な状態になるために
OK
OK
So this is the second part of what I'm going to say
これが私がこれから言いたいことの後半です
In addition to the competitive behavior we talked about at the beginning, cells
冒頭で話した競争行動に加えて、細胞は
The second part is that cells also cooperate
2番目の部分は細胞も協力するということです
make it act
行動させる
Then I will now enter the third topic
それでは、３番目の議題に入ります。
This is quite an interesting story
これはなかなか興味深い話ですね
i often like to say this
私はよくこれを言うのが好きです
I would like to put my research under an interesting topic
興味深いテーマで研究を進めたいと思っています
So this tells the story first
これが最初に物語を伝えます
it's an interesting story
興味深い話です
Maybe some of you have also heard this story on the Internet
もしかしたらネットでこの話を聞いたことがある人もいるかもしれません
can also be seen
も見ることができます
Or I wrote about it in House Weekly
あるいは、毎週家の中でそれについて書きました
that is
あれは
Here is a study in London, UK
イギリス・ロンドンでの留学はこちら
Many people may have traveled to London
ロンドンに旅行に行ったことがある人も多いのではないでしょうか？
know that london is a very old city
ロンドンは非常に古い都市であることを知っています
There's a big problem with this ancient city
この古代都市には大きな問題がある
That is to say, its roads have been messed up for hundreds of years
つまり、その道路は何百年もの間混乱していたということです
We saw it said in an area next to a train station
駅の隣のエリアでそう言われているのを見た
you see this area
このエリアが見えます
see this yellow is the big road
見てください、この黄色が大きな道です
It doesn't love the way of mental peace like our lieutenant colonel
私たちの中佐のように精神的な平和の道を愛さない
very straight like this
このようにとてもまっすぐです
it's messed up like this
こんなふうにめちゃくちゃです
Then you should not ignore that there are many small roads inside.
その場合、内部には小さな道路がたくさんあることを無視してはなりません。
very very complicated
とてもとても複雑
then we know this
そうすれば私たちはこれを知っています
Immigrants in the UK are probably different from us
イギリスの移民はおそらく私たちとは違う
We like to use Zhongxiao East Road Section 1 Section 2 Section 3 Section 4 Section 5
忠孝東路 セクション 1 セクション 2 セクション 3 セクション 4 セクション 5 を好んで使用します。
It's easy to remember, right?
覚えやすいですよね？
Each of their roads may be called a name for a small section
それぞれの道路は小さなセクションの名前と呼ばれる場合があります
A short paragraph is called a name
短い段落は名前と呼ばれます
So there is a big problem here, that is,
ここで大きな問題が発生します。
What to do with inheritance car drivers in London
ロンドンで遺産相続車の運転手をどうするか
There may be tens of thousands of paths
何万ものパスがあるかもしれない
Then there may be thousands of attractions
そうすれば何千ものアトラクションがあるかもしれません
Then inherit the car driver
その後、車の運転手を継承します
Let me tell you which road I want to go to, a certain scenic spot
行きたい道を教えて、とある景勝地
it's about to know
それはもうすぐ分かることだ
This study was before GPS
この研究はGPS以前のものでした
so let's talk
それで話しましょう
Now that the GPS comes out, of course this problem will be gone.
GPSの登場により、当然この問題は解消されます。
So we know that some people are very good at recording
ですから、録音がとても上手な人もいるということはわかっています。
you just talk to him
あなたはただ彼と話してください
He knew right away how to get there
彼はそこへ行く方法をすぐに知っていた
That is to say, we know that he is old
つまり、私たちは彼が年老いていることを知っています
The so-called Name-A-Gation means
いわゆるName-A-Gationとは、
The concept of controlling space in space is very good
宇宙で空間をコントロールするというコンセプトはとても良いです
He knew right away how to get there
彼はそこへ行く方法をすぐに知っていた
Which road is the fastest way to go recently?
最近どの道を行くのが一番早いですか?
London heritage car drivers have a very special
ロンドンのヘリテージカーのドライバーには特別な思いがある
it is more black
もっと黒いです
black cab driver black cab driver
黒いタクシーの運転手 黒いタクシーの運転手
They need special training
彼らには特別な訓練が必要です
They can't just say they want to be taxi drivers
彼らはただタクシー運転手になりたいと言うわけにはいかない
be a taxi driver
タクシー運転手になる
Because this road is too complicated
この道は複雑すぎるから
So their training is actually
つまり、彼らのトレーニングは実際には
like we go to college
私たちが大学に通っているように
they say average training down
彼らは平均的なトレーニングが減少していると言います
to get this driver's license
この運転免許証を取得するには
about two to four years
2年から4年くらい
two to four years
2年から4年
So it's not easy
だからそれは簡単ではない
Then you have to go through a lot of exams in the middle
そして途中でたくさんの試験を受けなければなりません
The small test and the big test look like this
小テストと大テストはこんな感じ
In fact, many people fail
実は失敗する人も多い
No way to get this to drive like this
これをこのように運転させる方法はありません
During their training over the course of two to four years
2年から4年の研修期間中
They feel as if we are studying
まるで勉強しているかのように感じられます
We are learning a major
私たちは専攻を学んでいます
After two to four years, these people
2年から4年後、この人たちは
they feel like
彼らはこう言いたい気分だ
This ability is definitely related to the ability to control space
この能力は間違いなく空間を制御する能力に関連しています
Spatial control
空間制御
For example, let me tell you now
たとえば、今教えてください
How to get to the Forbidden City
紫禁城への行き方
can anyone get this right now
誰でもすぐにこれを手に入れることができますか
report it to the boss
それを上司に報告する
Maybe some people in there will know soon
もしかしたら中にはすぐに分かる人もいるかもしれない
from which road the whole past
どの道からの過去全体
Then some people say I am GPS
そうすると、私が GPS だと言う人もいます
I can't pass without me
私なしでは通れない
this is
これは
There is no space, there is no difference
スペースはない、違いはない
so they go and say
それで彼らは行って言います
Why do some people have this
なぜ一部の人はこれを持っているのでしょうか
can pass this exam
この試験に合格できます
trained and passed the exam
訓練を受けて試験に合格した
What the hell happened in his head
彼の心の中で何が起こったのでしょうか？
what's going on in the brain
脳の中で何が起こっているのか
they found out
彼らは知った
in the hippocampus of the brain
脳の海馬で
his back area
彼の背中の部分
this place
この場所
as long as you pass this exam
この試験に合格する限り
And especially the longer you drive
そして特に長く運転するほど
that area will get a little bit bigger
そのエリアはもう少し大きくなります
the back half of the hippocampus
海馬の後ろ半分
there will be a little
少しあるでしょう
that use this
これを使うのは
We call this image development
これがイメージ開発と呼ばれるものです
this came out looking
これは探して出てきた
It's really a little bigger
本当はもう少し大きいんですが
and this
この
as long as you drive
運転している限り
more familiar people
もっと身近な人たち
the bigger the place
場所が大きいほど
Then you go to see those who failed
それからあなたは失敗した人たちに会いに行きます
maybe a year and a half
たぶん1年半
then what
じゃあ何
that place didn't get bigger
あの場所は大きくならなかった
this place doesn't get any bigger
この場所はこれ以上大きくならない
this is very special
これはとても特別なことです
That is to say, there is a linear relationship between
つまり、間には線形関係があります。
say you are more familiar
あなたはもっと詳しいと言う
the longer you train
長くトレーニングすればするほど
then you this
それならあなたはこれ
The longer you drive, the bigger your place will be
長く運転すればするほど、あなたの場所は大きくなります
This increased size has something to do with it
このサイズの増加には何か関係があります
Then you lose no one
そうすれば誰も失うことはありません
challenge
チャレンジ
Said, maybe this is not related to the experience of driving a taxi
たぶん、これはタクシーの運転経験とは関係ないと思います
And maybe this is just a London air move
そしておそらくこれは単なるロンドン空路の移動です
Work is stressful
仕事のプレッシャー
Then your place may have something to do with your resistance to stress
そうすると、あなたの居場所があなたのストレス耐性と関係があるかもしれません
or something
か何か
Then they study very simple
それから彼らはとても簡単な勉強をします
That's easy. I'll just find out the bus driver in London.
それは簡単です。ロンドンのバスの運転手を調べてみます。
That bus driver breathes dirty air every day.
あのバスの運転手は毎日汚れた空気を吸っています。
And it's a lot of pressure every day.
そして毎日かなりのプレッシャーです。
Let's look at this area of ​​their brain
彼らの脳のこの領域を見てみましょう
no increase in
増加しない
So in other words, this is driving a taxi
つまり、これはタクシーを運転しているのです
A special phenomenon of the driver is like this
ドライバーの特殊現象はこんな感じ
Then they also put some
それから彼らはまたいくつかを置きました
Later, he stopped, and he said that I am in my 40s and I am going to retire.
その後、彼は立ち止まり、私は40代で退職するつもりだと言いました。
Then you found out that the longer you retire
その後、退職が長くなるほど、
That place shrinks back a little bit like this
あの場所はこうやって少し縮んでいく
Obviously, that place has a very obvious relationship with the control of space.
明らかに、その場所は空間の制御と非常に明白な関係があります。
this is an interesting report
これは興味深いレポートです
Then everyone here says
すると、ここにいるみんなが言います
what about london
ロンドンはどうですか
Is there any in New York?
ニューヨークにもあるんですか？
or does paris have
それともパリにはありますか
Will the genetic design of Taipei City look like this?
台北市の遺伝子設計はこんな感じになるのだろうか？
Does anyone know
誰か知っていますか
In fact, if you go to New York or Paris or Taipei
実際、ニューヨークやパリや台北に行ったら
Our path is actually more
私たちの道は実際にはもっと長いです
Four squares, right?
4つの正方形ですよね？
especially new york
特にニューヨーク
And the roads in New York are pretty easy to remember, right?
それに、ニューヨークの道は覚えやすいですよね？
12345678910 Pass like this
12345678910 このようにパスしてください
That 12345 looks like this
その12345はこんな感じです
So their driver
それで彼らの運転手は
Your brain trains you to control this ability
あなたの脳はこの能力を制御するように訓練されます
There is no need to go to such a strong training like this
そんなに厳しいトレーニングをする必要はありません
So it can reflect that
したがって、それを反映することができます
To become a skill design in London
ロンドンでスキルデザインになるには
your training is very solid
あなたのトレーニングはとてもしっかりしています
then a certain area of ​​your brain
次に、脳の特定の領域
It really has something to do with space control
それは実際には空間制御と関係があります
Then after you enter the training
そして研修に入ってからは
Your area will grow a little bit like this
あなたのエリアはこのように少しずつ成長します
So this in their same research
これは彼らの同じ研究で
when looking in other cities
他の都市を見てみると
There is no such phenomenon in the ongoing period in other places.
他の場所では進行中のこのような現象はありません。
It's an interesting subject
興味深い話題ですね
so why
なぜ
That actually has a price
実はそれには値段があるんです
Let me tell you about this first
まずこれについてお話しさせてください
In fact, many different industries
実は、さまざまな業界で
if you've been training somewhere
どこかでトレーニングをしていれば
There may be some changes in some parts of your brain
脳の一部に変化が起こる可能性があります
some changes
いくつかの変更
Is there a price for this change?
この変更には料金がかかりますか?
It means you are very good now
つまり、あなたは今とても元気です
When you become a professional taxi driver
プロのタクシードライバーになると
Then you'll be able to know where to go
そうすればどこに行けばいいかわかるよ
Your ability to control space has improved
空間をコントロールする能力が向上しました
In fact, they found that
実際、彼らは次のことを発見しました。
Hey, the instant memory ability of these people for an image
おい、この人たちの画像の瞬間記憶能力は
In fact, there are a little worse than the average person
実際には、平均的な人よりも少し悪い人もいます
when one of your abilities becomes stronger
あなたの能力の一つが強くなったとき
help him use your nervous system
彼があなたの神経系を使えるように手伝ってください
When using this function
この機能を使用する場合
Some of your other abilities may disappear like this
あなたの他の能力のいくつかはこのように消えるかもしれません
That's quite an interesting way of saying it.
なかなか面白い言い方ですね。
That
それか
How did the brain change?
脳はどのように変化したのでしょうか？
Why is it about remembering something
なぜ何かを思い出すことなのか
Then it will make a slight change somewhere in you like this
そうすれば、このようにあなたのどこかに小さな変化が起こります
Well, there's actually a theory
まあ、実際には理論があります
What this theory actually says is
この理論が実際に述べていることは、
Yeah, it's worth mentioning that these people aren't young people or kids.
そうですね、ここで言っておきたいのは、この人たちは若者や子供ではないということです。
We know that the brains of children or young adults may still be developing, so it changes like this
子供や若者の脳はまだ発達段階にある可能性があるため、次のように変化することがわかっています。
But these adults are in their twenties
でもこの大人たちは20代ですよ
The brain is actually quite fixed like this
実は脳はこのようにかなり固定されているのです
But there will still be some changes
でもまだ変更点はあるだろう
How did this change come about?
この変化はどのようにして生じたのでしょうか?
We are saying that our memories have a structural plasticity
私たちの記憶には構造的な可塑性があると言っているのです。
The credibility of the structure means that its structure can still be changed
構造の信頼性は、その構造がまだ変更される可能性があることを意味します
when we remember something
私たちが何かを思い出すとき
This thing if we go through many times of training
何度も訓練を重ねるとこうなる
I remember when I was very familiar
とても親しかった頃を思い出します
There may be a structural change
構造的な変化があるかもしれない
The structure is generally the change in the synapse we just talked about
構造は一般に、先ほど話したシナプスの変化です。
A synapse is where two nerve cells meet
シナプスは2つの神経細胞が出会う場所です
Right, the place where the axon meets the tachyon just mentioned
そう、軸索とタキオンが出会う場所です。
synaptic changes
シナプスの変化
Then there is a meaning map
それから意味マップがあります
For example, the junction of these two nerve cells
たとえば、これら 2 つの神経細胞の接合部
this prominent place
この目立つ場所
Then there are some molecular mechanisms here that we won't talk about
ここには、話さない分子メカニズムがいくつかあります。
It is possible that the protrusion will become larger
出っ張りが大きくなる可能性があります
or split into two
もしくは二つに分けるか
touch more strongly
もっと強く触れて
tighter
よりきつい
it can make a dramatic difference
劇的な違いを生むことができる
So how do we do this experiment?
では、この実験はどのように行うのでしょうか?
In fact, ours is actually a small experiment.
実際、私たちの実験は小さな実験です。
But I also thought it was an interesting experiment
でも、面白い実験だとも思いました
Of course we can't make it too complicated
もちろん、あまり複雑にすることはできません
We're going to use this larva of the fruit fly
このショウジョウバエの幼虫を使います
If you can see this
これを見ることができれば
here is one
ここに一つあります
Did you notice the difference between the two larvae?
2匹の幼虫の違いに気づきましたか？
Let's take a look again
もう一度見てみましょう
is there one here
ここにありますか
little bit
若干
here is one
ここに一つあります
This one runs fast
これは速く走る
Something at the same time came here
同時に何かがここにやって来た
It seems that this one is not willing to climb
どうやらこちらは登る気がないようだ
in place like this
このような場所で
Then we found out that
それから私たちはそれを知りました
These larvae crawl slowly like this
この幼虫はこうやってゆっくり這っていきます
it's this prominent
こんなに目立つんだよ
It is easier for the motor nerve cells to protrude from the inner surface of the muscle
運動神経細胞が筋肉の内面から突出しやすくなる
But if this larva that's been crawling very fast
でももしこの幼虫がとても速く這っていたら
Its prominence will grow a little more complicated
その顕著性はもう少し複雑になります
And this sure enough larva research is relatively simple
そして、この確かな幼虫の研究は比較的簡単です
That means we only have to do it for about 8 hours
つまり、8時間くらいやるだけで済みます
we saw that
私たちはそれを見ました
Already crawling fast and crawling slowly stand out
もう早く這うのとゆっくり這うのが目立つ
There is a big difference in this growth ratio, like this
この成長率にはこんな感じで大きな差があります
This means that after we become adults,
つまり、私たちが大人になってからも、
Our brains are still somewhat forgiven
私たちの脳はまだある程度許されています
when you have been training in a certain place
ある場所でトレーニングをしているとき
The power of your place will become stronger
あなたの場所の力が強くなる
But at the same time it is possible that some will lose
しかし同時に、失う人もいる可能性がある
Everything is the same
すべて同じです
This is a very important concept to tell you about
これは皆さんに伝えておきたい非常に重要な概念です
In fact, our brains have just started talking about a lot of protruding things.
実際、私たちの脳は、多くの突出した事柄について話し始めたばかりです。
There are more than 14 protrusions in a brain
脳には14個以上の突起がある
Those highlights are recording our life
それらのハイライトは私たちの人生を記録しています
Bit by bit like this
このように少しずつ
your life experience what you remember
あなたの人生経験、あなたが覚えていること
That's a lot, it's like one
それはたくさんです、それは1つのようです
A previous recorder
以前のレコーダー
What is this called, a flow machine or something?
これは何と呼ばれるものですか、フローマシンか何かですか？
You record it, every time you experience something
何かを経験するたびに記録するだけです
You might just record these things in there
これらをそこに記録するだけかもしれません
Then you just remember to call it out next time like this
そうしたら、次回このように呼ぶことを忘れないでください
OK, it's as if our brain has a record of this
OK、まるで私たちの脳がこれを記録しているようです
So the highlight of this new Labs is
この新しいラボのハイライトは、
It may be that we accumulate various experiences in our brains
私たちの脳には様々な経験が蓄積されているのかもしれません
Memories, so if you listen to me today
思い出だから今日聞いてくれたら
Speech and then if you remember the representative said
スピーチ、そして覚えているなら代表者はこう言った
I've left some notes in your salient
あなたの顕著な部分にいくつかのメモを残しました
then this is
それならこれは
that last
那最後
to mention
言及する
We're actually a favorite subject of late
実は私たちは最近のお気に入りのテーマなのです
That's the one from Sudo
それは須藤さんのやつです
Variety
バラエティ
Diversity and complexity
多様性と複雑さ
Diversity goes without saying
多様性は言うまでもありません
We've just emphasized a lot
かなり強調してきましたが、
look at every nerve cell
あらゆる神経細胞を観察してください
this ontology
このオントロジー
We started with nerve cells
私たちが始めた神経細胞
ontology
オントロジー
this is its speed
これがそのスピードです
Each speed grows very
それぞれの速度が非常に成長します
very big difference
差異非常大
look different
異なって見えます
This is basically defined
これは基本的に定義されています
each nerve cell
それぞれの神経細胞
different kinds
異なる種類
This also has a lot to do with its function
これはその機能にも大きく関係しています
look different
異なって見えます
Its function may be different
機能が異なる場合があります
this
これ
In our four nerves
私たちの4つの神経では
actually a lot
実際にはたくさん
this kind of
このたぐいの
speed
速度
it has some features
いくつかの特徴があります
For example, we can see that
たとえば、次のことがわかります。
exist
存在
inside the eyeball
眼球の内側
The speed of the four nerves
4つの神経の速度
you see say
ほら言うね
One by one is actually arranged
実際に一つ一つ並べていきます
fairly neat
かなりきちんとした
and you feel like it has
そしてあなたはそれが起こったように感じます
certain one
ある人
a sense of domain
ドメインの感覚
have their own field
自分のフィールドを持っている
this one
これです
with this one
これと
probably a certain one
おそらく特定のもの
a distance like this
このくらいの距離
Then everyone has a
それなら誰もが持っている
one
一個
a speed
速度
such a certain field
そんなある分野
We know that our eyes need to sense a few things
私たちの目はいくつかのことを感知する必要があることを知っています
One is to feel the color, right?
一つは色を感じることですよね？
The second is to feel a type, a pattern, and a contrast
2つ目は、タイプ、パターン、コントラストを感じることです
or a boundary line
あるいは境界線
when we see something
私たちが何かを見るとき
where or how its boundaries
その境界線はどこで、どのようにして
The third thing to probably look at is a sporty
3番目に注目すべきは、スポーティなデザインです。
movement of things
物の動き
You can talk about our vision mirror
当社のビジョンミラーについて話してください
It may have something to do with where something is in space
それは宇宙のどこに何かがあるかに関係があるかもしれない
It's the kind of neuron that fills the entire eye
それは目全体を満たす一種のニューロンです
covered with these dendrites
この樹状突起で覆われている
These dendrites can be quite funny sometimes
これらの樹状突起は非常に面白い場合があります
It has something to do with the directionality of the movement of the objects that my eyes see
それは私の目で見る物の動きの方向性と関係があります
We can have fun looking at the example
例を見て楽しむことができます
if you look carefully
よく見ると
One by one nerve cells can be seen
神経細胞が一つ一つ見える
You see the body of the cell, right?
細胞の本体が見えますよね？
Ontology we just talked about
先ほど話したオントロジー
This is an axon, a very long axon
これは軸索です、非常に長い軸索です
The axons of each nerve cell gather to
各神経細胞の軸索は集まって
go to the same place
同じ場所に行く
it this gathers together
これが集まるのは
extend into the brain
脳内まで伸びる
Another interesting thing is that this tree diagram
もう一つ興味深いのは、この樹形図です。
look at this tree diagram
この樹形図を見てください
Notice the consistency of these tree diagrams
これらの樹形図の一貫性に注目してください。
how are they
彼らはお元気ですか
It's all down and down
それはすべて落ち込んでいます
So you should be able to guess what the function of this thing is
したがって、このものの機能が何であるかを推測できるはずです
It may have something to do with detecting the direction of movement of objects outside
外部の物体の移動方向の検出と関係がある可能性があります
Then their research thinks that
彼らの研究では次のように考えられています。
This may have something to do with the direction some objects are running up
これは、いくつかのオブジェクトが上昇する方向と関係がある可能性があります
So within these four nerves
この 4 つの神経の中で
It can be seen that there are four kinds of trees, and some tree diagrams are the group that goes down.
4 種類の木があり、いくつかの樹形図がそのグループを下位にあることがわかります。
Some are to the right, some are to the left, some are up
一部は右、一部は左、一部は上
So at least basically we can detect some different directions
したがって、少なくとも基本的にはいくつかの異なる方向を検出できます
Let's go back to this dissatisfaction
この不満に戻りましょう
nerve cells of dissatisfaction
不満の神経細胞
So of course we're doing this experiment with fruit flies.
ですから、もちろん、私たちはショウジョウバエを使ってこの実験を行っています。
What about the fruit fly?
ショウジョウバエはどうでしょうか？
We saw that it was a larva
私たちはそれが幼虫であることを見ました
Then from the nerve cells in the body
そして体内の神経細胞から
You see, this is the body one by one
ほら、これがボディ一つ一つです
But its speed is not enough for the whole body
しかし、そのスピードは体全体にとって十分ではありません
You see this speed everywhere
このスピードはどこでも見られます
I often feel like the larva is wearing a gold and aluminum coat
幼虫が金とアルミニウムのコートを着ているように感じることがよくあります
Dissatisfied with the whole body like this
こんな全身に不満
This has a lot to do with the larva's ability to sense external stimuli.
これは幼虫の外部刺激を感知する能力と大きく関係しています。
This is mainly the induction of two stimuli
これは主に 2 つの刺激の誘発です。
It's a nerve limb called pain sensation
それは痛覚と呼ばれる神経肢です
feel something harmful
何か有害なものを感じる
Harmful stimuli from the outside world
外界からの有害な刺激
one is high temperature
一つは高温です
For example, if the temperature is higher than 45 degrees
たとえば、気温が45度を超えた場合、
You pierce it with a needle at 45 degrees
45度の角度で針で刺します
you'll find that the larvae will roll to the other side
幼虫が向こう側に転がっていくことがわかるでしょう
it has a scrolling behavior
スクロール動作があります
It can also feel strong light
強い光も感じられる
When stimulated by strong light, it will run in the other direction
強い光で刺激を受けると逆方向に走ります
So we can know that
それで私たちはそれを知ることができます
These speeds of the nerve serve two functions
これらの神経の速度は 2 つの機能を果たします。
One is to feel harmful
一つは有害だと感じること
second what else do you know
二番目に他に何を知っていますか
Is the direction of stimulation coming from right?
刺激の方向は正しいですか？
That's why you know what I want
だからこそ、あなたは私が何を望んでいるのか知っています
I'm going to run to the other side
向こう側へ走っていくよ
so show everyone this
だからこれをみんなに見せて
a movie
一個movie
This is always climbing
ここはいつも登ってます
Did you see that strong light stimulated it?
強い光が刺激したのが分かりましたか？
It escaped and crawled to the other side
逃げて向こう側へ這って行った
ok let's see again
わかりました、また見てみましょう
it crawls to the right
それは右に這う
Then suddenly a
それから突然、
glare
まぶしさ
it just avoids that direction
その方向を避けるだけです
So you could conceivably say
したがって、おそらく次のように言うことができます
Its whole body is covered with this
全身がこれで覆われています
This is what it says is a harmful irritant
これは有害な刺激物であると書かれているものです
a source of
の情報源
Because the larva under the strong light
幼虫は強い光の下にいるので、
May be sun-dried
天日干ししてもよい
dry it and it may die
乾燥させると死んでしまう可能性があります
It must have this sure-fire larva
この確実な幼虫がいるに違いない
may have to hide in food
食べ物の中に隠れなければならないかもしれない
Then a humid environment like this
このような湿気の多い環境では、
so it body it except
したがって、それはそれを除いてそれを本体とします
I know it's harmful
それが有害であることはわかっています
The way it needs to know the source of this light
この光の源を知る方法
So it covers the whole body when it is actually projected to the central nervous system
実際に中枢神経系に照射されると全身を覆うことになります。
It actually has a proper alignment
実際には適切な調整が行われています
Then you can know where the stimulus is coming from
そうすれば、その刺激がどこから来ているかがわかります
The research in our laboratory is actually to study several topics of this speed.
私たちの研究室では、実際にこの速度に関するいくつかのトピックを研究しています。
Then I will try to give a few interesting examples like this
次に、このような興味深い例をいくつか挙げてみましょう
In fact, we used a lot of relatively high-end microscopes
実際、私たちは比較的ハイエンドの顕微鏡をたくさん使用しました
You can see that this rate of growth has been moving
この成長率は推移していることがわかります
In fact, we can imagine that it is actually very similar to human beings.
実際、それは人間に非常によく似ていると想像できます。
Our speed is actually the speed inside the body may be growing all the time
私たちのスピードは実は体内のスピードであり、常に成長しているのかもしれない
It's always changing, it's always moving around like this
常に変化している いつもこうやって動き回っている
Then our microscope can see the movement of some molecules in the speed
すると、私たちの顕微鏡は、いくつかの分子の動きをその速度で見ることができます。
Then let's slowly tell some interesting stories like this
それではゆっくりとこんな面白い話をしましょう
Let's look at this first
まずはこれを見てみましょう
Let's take pictures of the dynamics at this speed
このスピードでダイナミックな写真を撮りましょう
Did you see any behavior
それで、どのような行動が見られましたか？
Actually, we saw how some dendrites
実際に、いくつかの樹状突起がどのように変化するかを観察しました。
is extending
延長中です
how about some
いくつかはどうですか
shrinking
収縮
Some of them are newborns
中には新生児もいます
Actually, one thing I find interesting is the behavior of repulsion
実は、私が面白いと思うのは、反発の挙動です。
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Both dendrites want to grow
両方の樹状突起が成長したい
Then what if they bump into each other
それで、もし彼らがぶつかったらどうするか
retracted
撤回された
You know, these dendrites all come out of the same nerve cell.
ご存知のとおり、これらの樹状突起はすべて同じ神経細胞から生じています。
You think it's the body of the same nerve cell
同じ神経細胞の本体だと思ってるの？
Then keep branching and branching
その後も分岐を繰り返していきます
then come out
それから出てくる
The growth of the dendrites
樹状突起の成長
it has two principles
それには2つの原則があります
There are two principles
原則は2つあります
Just now you saw the amount of dendrites that were dissatisfied from birth
たった今、あなたは不満を持って生まれた樹状突起の量を見ました
It is so long there are two principles
長いので原則は2つあります
one is to say how
1つは、どのように言うかです
It wants to dissatisfy the whole body as much as possible
できるだけ全身を不満にしたい
because you can't have a body have a place
体が無いから場所が無いんだよ
without that dendrite
その樹状突起がなければ
Then if the other side is exposed to high temperature or high
次に、反対側が高温または高温にさらされた場合、
If you are stimulated by the high gun light, you will not feel it
ハイガンライトで刺激されたら感じなくなるよ
that's dangerous
それは危険です
So you have to find a way to increase the speed all the time
したがって、常に速度を上げる方法を見つける必要があります
fill all the space like this
このようにすべてのスペースを埋めます
So it's this velocity that we call space filling
この速度を空間充填と呼んでいます
That is to say, where there is space, it will quickly extend it.
つまり、スペースがあるところはすぐに拡張します。
and then want to fill it up
そしてそれを埋めたい
what about the second one
2番目はどうですか
it has an evasive behavior
それは回避行動をとります
That is to say, it does not need two speeds in the same space
つまり、同じ空間に 2 つの速度は必要ありません。
touch together intertwine
触れ合う、絡み合う
then go fill it
それからそれを埋めて行きます
So often two speeds
多くの場合、2 つの速度
What happens when two speeds of the same nerve cell collide
同じ神経細胞の 2 つの速度が衝突すると何が起こるか
it shrank
縮んだ
One shrank or both shrank
片方が縮んだ、または両方が縮んだ
Because I don't want to cover the same place over and over again
同じところを何度も塗りたくないから
Then you can imagine that this is the most economical
そうすれば、これが最も経済的であると想像できます
Either the most efficient or a
最も効率的か、
You have to try to fill all the space
すべてのスペースを埋めるように努めなければなりません
But what if we don't want to have two speeds?
しかし、2 つの速度を使用したくない場合はどうすればよいでしょうか?
touch together and then this
一緒に触れて、そしてこれ
to intertwine
絡み合う
This is a study, that is, this space-filled neuron
これは研究、つまりこの空間に満ちたニューロンです
Then they will grow a lot of soil, and then try to fill this space as much as possible
それから彼らはたくさんの土を育て、この空間をできるだけ埋めようとします。
But they try not to touch each other
でも彼らはお互いに触れないようにしてる
So here's a picture, a sure enough picture kind of
これが写真です、確かに十分な写真です
Then you can see that many places are intertwined with each other.
すると、多くの場所が互いに絡み合っていることがわかります。
These two stick together
この二人がくっついてる
Then some years form a handful, these two stick together
それから数年が数年を経て、この2つはくっつきます
Do you have a serious habit?
深刻な癖がありますか？
They mean that when they meet together
彼らが意味するのは、一緒に会うとき
They don't know to separate
彼らは別れるということを知らない
together after we meet
会った後は一緒に
OK, so let’s ask, how does a normal dweller know
OK、それでは聞いてみましょう、普通の住人はどうやってそれを知っているのでしょうか？
avoidance
回避
We are talking about this now, and we are very particular about avoiding self-interest.
私たちは今このことについて話し合っていますが、私たちは私利私欲を避けることに非常にこだわっています。
To know how to avoid yourself like this, how does Sutu avoid yourself
このような自分を避ける方法を知りたいのですが、Sutu はどのように自分を避けるのでしょうか。
Then this is a very interesting mutation
これは非常に興味深い突然変異です
This gene is called Beware of the Sale of Schimarchy
この遺伝子は「スキマーキーの販売に注意してください」と呼ばれています。
just a soup
ただのスープ
It is neutralizing positive cell skin molecules like this
このように陽性細胞の皮膚分子を中和しています
it's a gene
それは遺伝子です
This gene can make 40,000 proteins
この遺伝子は40,000のタンパク質を作ることができます
One gene makes 40,000 proteins
1 つの遺伝子が 40,000 個のタンパク質を作る
the funny thing is to say
面白いのはこう言うことです
It's inside every nerve cell
それはあらゆる神経細胞の中にあります
The expressed protein is different
発現するタンパク質が違う
This is because gene splicing
それは遺伝子のスプライシングによるものです
one gene can make
1つの遺伝子で作ることができる
But it's inside every nerve cell
しかし、それはすべての神経細胞の中にあります
The expressed molecules are different
発現する分子が異なる
Because different splicing is different
スプライシングが異なると異なるため
So you could conceivably say
したがって、おそらく次のように言うことができます
Each nerve cell expresses only a specific
それぞれの神経細胞は特定の機能のみを発現します。
protein out
プロテインアウト
The same gene can express different proteins
同じ遺伝子でも異なるタンパク質を発現できる
Then this is like its ID card
これがIDカードのようなものです
That is to say
つまり
I just want to express this
ただこれを表現したいのです
express one of the proteins
タンパク質の1つを発現させる
from a class of proteins like this
このようなタンパク質のクラスから
Then these proteins will go to
次に、これらのタンパク質は次の場所に移動します。
speed surface up
スピードが上がる
So when it's two speeds
それで、それが2つの速度のとき
when we touch each other
私たちがお互いに触れたとき
then see
それから見てください
This protein is the same
このタンパク質も同じです
so what do we do
どうしようか
hold on to each other
お互いを抱きしめて
It's a very simple truth
それはとても単純な真実です
That is to say we give
つまり、私たちは与えるのです
One identity card per nerve cell
神経細胞ごとに 1 つの ID カード
Its two dendrites have to touch together
2 つの樹状突起が接触している必要があります
they can check
彼らはチェックできる
we are the same
我々は同じだ
Then we avoid it like this
それから私たちはこのようにそれを避けます
So the dendrites of this same neuron
したがって、この同じニューロンの樹状突起は
must avoid
避けなければなりません
This is an interesting example
これは興味深い例です
The other thing to avoid is actually
もう一つ避けるべきことは、実は
quite special that is to say
つまりかなり特別です
we just saw that
私たちはちょうどそれを見ました
The same goes for the nerve cells on the retina
網膜上の神経細胞も同様です
Each cell occupies a space like this
各セルはこのようなスペースを占めます
So we can see that
それでわかります
this dendrite
この樹状突起
from different cells
異なる細胞から
the same nerve cell
同じ神経細胞
different dendrites
異なる樹状突起
This is the red cell body here
これが赤血球本体です
This is a green cell body
これは緑色の細胞体です
their dendrites grow
彼らの樹状突起は成長します
just grow up, right?
ただ成長するだけですよね？
they'll get very, very close to each other
彼らはお互いにとてもとても近づくでしょう
what we just said
私たちが今言ったこと
It's going to cover its entire body with dendrites
全身を樹状突起で覆うことになる
So they should be as full as possible
したがって、それらはできるだけいっぱいである必要があります
But they don't want to be intertwined
でも彼らは絡みたくないんだよ
so you see some details
それで、いくつかの詳細がわかります
For example, the red and green
たとえば、赤と緑
almost all close
ほぼ全部近い
but not together
でも一緒ではない
do not touch together
一緒に触れないでください
They're going to keep building a field
彼らはフィールドを作り続けるつもりだ
The field is bigger the better
フィールドは広ければ広いほど良い
we can get very close
私たちはとても近づくことができます
but got very very close
しかし、非常に非常に近づいた
They avoid it when approached
近づくと避けてしまう
It's just that I don't want to occupy your space
ただあなたのスペースを占領したくないだけです
you don't come to occupy my space
あなたは私のスペースを占領するために来たわけではありません
Here is a very simple experiment
これは非常に簡単な実験です
to explain this matter
この件について説明するために
In fact, what we just said is very simple.
実際、私たちが今述べたことは非常に単純です。
you use a laser
あなたはレーザーを使用します
kill this cell
この細胞を殺す
Of course those speeds are gone.
もちろん、その速度は失われます。
so it's easy
だから簡単です
everyone knows the answer
誰もが答えを知っています
just grow up
ただ成長するだけ
Come over and help him cover
こっちに来て、彼がカバーするのを手伝ってください
this has an area
これには面積があります
so just cover it
だからそれをカバーするだけ
So this is a very simple example
これは非常に単純な例です
they will build their own domain
彼らは独自のドメインを構築するでしょう
But they can't exchange each other
でもお互いに交換することはできない
So in this body section
したがって、この本文セクションでは
There are actually only three of these neurons
実際にはこれらのニューロンは 3 つだけです
Three blue, green, yellow
青、緑、黄色の3本
build your own domain
独自のドメインを構築する
not interchangeable
交換不可能
another said
別の人が言いました
speed self avoidance
スピード自己回避
Then let's look at this example
それではこの例を見てみましょう
In fact, everyone, take a look at this moving
実際にこの動きを見てみましょう
watch the color change
色の変化を見てください
did you see
あなたは見ましたか
Which color is the tree diagram we are talking about
私たちが話している樹形図は何色ですか
green, right?
緑色ですよね？
So we just talked about a psycho
それで私たちはサイコについて話しました
Then when you look at the red, there are grids of cells, are there any?
次に、赤色を見ると、セルのグリッドがあります。
That's epidermal cells
それが表皮細胞です
Those tree diagrams actually grow under the epidermal cells
これらの樹形図は実際に表皮細胞の下で成長します
It has a very tight bond with epidermal cells
表皮細胞と非常に強い結合を持っています
Underneath this epidermal cell is this
この表皮細胞の下にはこれがあります
one layer of this
これの1層
The tree map just grows under this skin
ツリーマップはこのスキンの下で成長するだけです
So outside stimuli
つまり外部からの刺激が
These tree diagrams can feel
これらの樹形図は次のように感じられます。
Then send the signal over like this
次に、このように信号を送信します
so
それで
like we actually have researched a little bit of this stuff
私たちは実際にこのことについて少し調べたようです
we found out that
私たちはそれを知りました
Eh
えー
This is an epidermal cell
これは表皮細胞です
it's a glove like this
こんな手袋です
one by one like this
こうやって一つ一つ
it is tree map red
ツリーマップレッドです
It grows under the epidermis like this
表皮の下にはこのように生えています
may see say
言うかもしれない
Below this tree diagram
この樹形図の下に
There are also some green proteins
緑色のタンパク質もいくつかあります
It's the same protein as this epidermal cell protein
この表皮細胞のタンパク質と同じタンパク質です
So actually this epidermal cell is here
実はこの表皮細胞はここにあるのです
is helping the tree graph grow
樹形図の成長を助けています
assisting its growth
その成長を支援する
so that it can be stabilized on this epidermal cell
この表皮細胞上に安定化できるように
it grows
それは成長します
Epidermal cells may have some protein secretion
表皮細胞はタンパク質を分泌している可能性があります
stick it on top
上に貼り付けます
let it stabilize
安定させてください
Then we just talked about what the tree diagram has
次に、樹形図が何を持っているかについて話しました。
There are extended and retracted, right?
伸びる部分と縮む部分がありますよね？
if it is so stable
そんなに安定してるなら
The tree diagram is less likely to shrink back
樹形図が収縮する可能性が低くなります
it grows at a constant distance like this
このように一定の距離で成長します
Those are epidermal cells
それが表皮細胞です
of course we know this
もちろん私たちはそれを知っています
not entirely good
完全に良くない
It also sometimes plays this
時々これも演奏します
double face role
ダブルフェイス役
What we just saw was an epidermal cell
私たちが今見たのは表皮細胞でした
A pair of tree diagrams
一対の樹形図
growing a stable one
安定したものを育てる
support
支持
So here is the same group of epidermal cells
これが同じ表皮細胞のグループです
But they are actually eating the tree diagram
しかし、彼らは実際に樹形図を食べています。
You see this tree diagram
この樹形図がわかります
This treemap is dying
このツリーマップは死につつあります
you see the whole and disappear
あなたは全体を見て消えてしまう
In this movie that was shot for about half an hour
約30分にわたって撮影されたこの映画では、
You're swallowed when you see a tree diagram
樹形図を見ると飲み込まれてしまう
You see that this tree diagram is cut off more specifically
この樹形図の一部がより特別であることがわかります。
You see a little bit of the tail being pulled away like this
このように尾が少し引っ張られているのがわかります
Pull it off and it disappears like this
外すとこのように消えます
So this epidermal cell also
つまりこの表皮細胞も
This is really double-faced
これは本当に二面性がある
He supported the growth of this tree map in the early days
彼は初期の頃、このツリーマップの成長をサポートしました
Gobble up the treemap at a later stage
後の段階でツリーマップを飲み込む
It's an interesting experiment
面白い実験ですね
I appreciate it every time I watch a movie
映画を見るたびに感謝します
how to swallow this
これをどうやって飲み込むか
This tree diagram this neuron is here
この樹形図 このニューロンはここにあります
Ontology is here
オントロジーはここにあります
It's very complicated with several strands
いくつかの糸が絡み合って非常に複雑です
Its tree diagram is going to grow
成長する樹形図
to fill the space like this
このようにスペースを埋めるために
we can see say this tree stand
この木が立っているのが見えます
look at this purple one
この紫色のものを見てください
it's green
これは緑です
this black like this
この黒はこんな感じ
And then they went to shoot this inside
そして彼らは屋内でこれを撮影しに行きました
signal before being swallowed
飲み込まれる前の合図
If you look at the picture on the right
右の写真を見てみると
did you see
あなたは見ましたか
This looks like this lightning
これは稲妻のように見えます
Suddenly one lighted up, right?
突然片方が点灯しましたよね？
The first root is here, the second root is there
最初のルートがここにあり、2 番目のルートがそこにあります
Then we look at this diagram that means
次に、この図を見てみましょう。つまり、
It's not a schematic, it's just
それは概略図ではなく、ただの図式です
an image of that single time
あの時のイメージ
then this one
それからこれ
this one
これです
suddenly light up together
突然一緒に明るくなる
Then this one will be swallowed
そうするとこれも飲み込まれてしまう
next time this
次回はこれ
all lit up
すべて点灯しました
Then this one will be swallowed
そうするとこれも飲み込まれてしまう
that seems to mean
それは意味があるようです
This diagram is not
この図はそうではありません
all together all together like this
みんなで一緒にこうして
In fact there is a
実際には、
have a sense of order
秩序の感覚がある
That is to say, one of them is swallowed whole.
つまり、片方を丸呑みしてしまうのです。
Then the others are later
それでは他のものはまた後ほど
just got swallowed like this
このように飲み込まれたばかりです
there seems to be a signal
信号があるようです
must accumulate to a certain
一定まで蓄積する必要がある
Above critical point
臨界点以上
Then this root diagram will be swallowed like this
すると、このルート図はこのように飲み込まれます
This is actually a bit like some
これは実際にはいくつかのことに似ています
Let's look at one of the neurotransmitter disorders
神経伝達物質の障害の 1 つを見てみましょう
diagram, this is a
図、これは
a cerebellar spinal atrophy
小脳脊髄萎縮症
a certain kind, this first kind
ある種、この最初の種類
Then you saw this one
それからこれを見ます
Pokinji Cell
ポキンジ細胞
This art picture originally looked very dense
このアート画像はもともと非常に緻密に見えました
Like this, there are several like this
このように、このようなものがいくつかあります
It should be said that when the disease occurs
病気が発症したときに言うべきことは、
Sometimes it's like one of them is missing
時々、どちらかが欠けているような気がする
one missing like this
このように1つ欠けています
The rest of the place looks pretty good.
残りの場所はかなり良いようです。
not bad
悪くない
So this seems to respond
それでこれは反応するようです
This can be done as a pattern
これはパターンとして実行できます
study some diseases
いくつかの病気を勉強する
In fact, we often say
実際、私たちはよく言います
During development these articulations
開発中、これらのアーティキュレーションは
It has a lot to do with our nerve cells
それは私たちの神経細胞と大きく関係しています
That seems to grow as much as possible
それは可能な限り成長するようです
The more secretive the better
秘密主義であればあるほど良い
In fact, our development is often not like this
実際、私たちの開発はこのようにはいかないことがよくあります
We started by talking about our
私たちは自分たちのことについて話すことから始めました
Like cells, we do enough
細胞のように、私たちは十分なことをします
Then in some places how to
それから、いくつかの場所ではどうすればよいですか
let this cell die
この細胞を死なせてください
and then be able to construct
そして構築できるようになります
something pretty with a stretched eye
目を伸ばした何かかわいいもの
The picture is the same
絵も同じですよ
We have a nice model here
ここに素敵なモデルがあります
After the dendrite grows
樹状突起が成長した後
at some point it has to be broken
いつかは壊さなければならない
Then keep the cell body
その後、細胞体を保持します
Axons also remain
軸索も残る
That's only if the dendrites are all broken.
樹状突起がすべて壊れているだけです。
What about after it's broken?
壊れた後はどうなるのでしょうか？
This nerve cell can then grow a new tree protrusion
この神経細胞は新しい木の突起を成長させることができます
Execute the new function like this
このように新しい関数を実行します
So this dendrite actually has a modification during development
つまり、この樹状突起には開発中に実際に変更が加えられています
or the process of shrinking
または縮小の過程
fix it like this
このように見せてください
Well, this is actually in human development
まあ、これは実際に人類の発達の中にあります
In fact, this phenomenon is also very clear
実はこの現象も非常に明らかです
is what we know to say
それは私たちが知っていることです
newborn baby
新生児
It is between 0 and 2 years old
0歳から2歳くらいまでです
we look at this line
私たちはこの行を見ます
this normal this line
この普通のこの線
it actually keeps increasing
実際には増え続けています
The dendrites will keep increasing, right?
樹状突起はどんどん増えていきますよね？
It will increase to 0 when it is about 2 years old
2歳くらいになると0になります
But then the dendrites start to decrease
しかしその後、樹状突起は減少し始めます
At first it will be reduced to a normal number like this
最初はこのように通常の数値に減ります
Then this may mean doing a little more at the beginning
そうすると、最初はもう少しやるということになるかもしれません
Then let the neurons form different grades
次に、ニューロンにさまざまなグレードを形成させます
If it's too much then fix it up
多すぎる場合は修正してください
it's a simple idea
それは単純な考えです
Then we found that the scientist
その後、科学者が
We found this diagram that says this modification
この変更を示す図を見つけました
It's actually very important not to grow too much
実は成長しすぎないことがとても重要です
For example, when you are autistic
たとえば、自閉症の場合
Some of
いくつかの
Children will find that his art diagram begins
子どもたちは、彼のアート図が始まることに気づくでしょう。
is more long
もっと長いです
then too much
それなら多すぎる
Then he will have the modified
そうすれば彼は修正されたものを手に入れるでしょう
But it has not been modified to a normal phenomenon like this
しかし、このような通常の現象には修正されていません
that in certain other developments like this
このような他の特定の開発では
traditionally called schizophrenia
伝統的に統合失調症と呼ばれる
It is now called Sijue Sitiao
現在はSijue Sitiaoと呼ばれています
this red line
この赤い線
you can see say
言うことがわかります
when he was growing
彼が成長していたとき
It is normal to increase
増えるのが普通
at the top
頂点で
He came down with too much grooming
彼が降りてきたとき、彼は手入れが行き届いていた
too much retouching
修飾過多
so
それで
This may be a possibility that caused his thoughts.
これが彼の考えを引き起こした可能性があります。
If you are mentally handicapped, that means
精神障害者は
It may not be long enough at the beginning
最初は長さが足りないかもしれません
Then it will be too much to fix it like this
そうするとこのまま直すのは大変です
So he is also better than the normal picture
だから彼も通常の写真よりも優れています
also slightly
それもわずかに
So this is our epiphysis during development
これが発達中の骨端です
There is a process of adding and modifying
追加・修正の工程がございます
We want to say that additions and modifications are normal numbers
追加と修正は正常な数であると言いたいのです
not only in development
開発中だけでなく
some geriatric diseases
いくつかの成人病
don't talk about geriatric diseases
成人病について話すな
later neurological diseases
その後の神経疾患
Alzheimer's disease
アルツハイマー病
Said that the increase in speed is more than
速度の向上は以上であると言われています
This is the body and speed of a normal nerve cell
これが正常な神経細胞の体積と速度です
We're seeing Alzheimer's brain degeneration
アルツハイマー病の脳変性が見られる
The speed of nerve cells is reduced very much
神経細胞の速度が大幅に低下します
under stress or anxiety
ストレスや不安の下で
under strong pressure
強い圧力の下で
Its speed will actually decrease accordingly.
実際の速度はそれに応じて低下します。
So this provides us with say
したがって、これにより私たちに発言権が与えられます
We want to study the relationship between speed and these diseases
スピードとこれらの病気の関係を研究したい
We have a body in our laboratory
私たちの実験室には死体があります
Studying this Fear of Spiritual Policing
霊的取り締まりの恐怖を研究する
This is mainly a doctor coming to our laboratory
これは主に私たちの研究室に来ている医師です
Very special. He hopes to use Guoying as a model to study the life cycle of Phra Chiang.
とても特別で、彼はプラチェンのライフサイクルを研究するためのモデルとして国営を使いたいと考えています。
It turned out to be very interesting, so I'll take a moment to report back
とても面白かったので、またレポートしたいと思います
Well, Pa Qingsheng is actually not a doctor, so this may not be very accurate.
まあ、Pa Qingsheng は実際には医師ではないので、これはあまり正確ではないかもしれません。
But Pa Qingsheng at least we know that there are a few characteristics
しかし、Pa Qingsheng には少なくともいくつかの特徴があることがわかっています。
That means fighting and slowing down when prohibited
つまり、禁止されている場合は戦闘し、減速することを意味します
Very stiff limbs and heel area Very unstable posture
手足とかかとが非常に硬い 姿勢が非常に不安定
Those who are interested can go online to watch some videos, which is actually very clear
興味のある方は、オンラインでいくつかのビデオを見ることができます。実際には非常にわかりやすいです。
So what I want to say is that in fact, about two thousand years later
そこで私が言いたいのは、実際には約二千年後、
During Phra Ching's birth, he found that many words caused
プラチンの誕生中に、彼は多くの言葉が原因となることを発見しました。
This is partly due to genetic mutations
これは部分的には遺伝子変異によるものです
Of course, there is another part that everyone thinks is related to the environment.
もちろん、誰もが環境に関係していると考えているもう一つの部分があります。
But there are different theories. Some people think it's mostly genetic.
しかし、さまざまな理論があり、主に遺伝によるものだと考える人もいます。
That's because the environmental factor is the most important factor
それは環境要因が最も重要な要因だからです
it's a matter of age
それは年齢の問題です
This happens when older
高齢になるとこういう事が起こる
Pagene's chances are higher
パジェネの可能性は高い
that sometimes you just because you have the gene
あなたがその遺伝子を持っているという理由だけで、時々あなたは
you do not know
あなたは知らない
It's just that people may die from various other factors
ただ、人は他のさまざまな要因で死ぬ可能性があります
Cancer, this, or injury, or something
ガンとかこれとか怪我とか
so
それで
so you just didn't
だからあなたはそうしないだけです
Didn't live long enough to say let your pagene happen
「あなたのページネを実現させましょう」と言えるほど長くは生きられなかった
But that said you might have this
しかし、それはあなたがこれを持っているかもしれないと言った
genetic mutation in
の遺伝子変異
That
それか
He will find that there are many genes in people
彼は人間には多くの遺伝子があることに気づくだろう
this
これ
They use this PRK Park the most
彼らはこの PRK パークを最もよく利用します
This one is named 12345678 to District 18
これは 12345678 という名前で、District 18 に割り当てられます。
That's their normal
それが彼らの普通だよ
The name of this gene that everyone is calling
みんなが呼んでいるこの遺伝子の名前
Then
それから
their protein or something
彼らのプロテインか何か
That
それか
I won't talk about it one by one
いちいち話さないよ
But here it is found that
しかし、ここで判明したのは、
many genes
多くの遺伝子
in the state camp
州キャンプで
Probably at least 60-70% of all genes
おそらく全遺伝子の少なくとも 60 ～ 70%
that's weird
それは変だ
The state camp only lives for 60 days
州キャンプの存続期間は60日間のみ
that person lives at least
あの人は少なくとも生きている
It takes sixty years for a person to get this
これを得るには人は60年かかる
Over 60 years old
60歳以上
over sixty-five years old
65歳以上
The gene born of that Depak
そのデパックから生まれた遺伝子
become so tall
とても背が高くなる
So why does this gene exist in the state-run
では、なぜこの遺伝子が国営企業に存在するのでしょうか。
In fact, the explanation is quite simple.
実際、その説明は非常に簡単です。
how about a lot of genes
遺伝子がたくさんあるのはどうですか
Actually it has its normal function
実際には通常の機能があります
It's just because the function of this gene has changed after the mutation
それはただ、突然変異によってこの遺伝子の機能が変わったからです
Then maybe something builds up in the body
そうすると体の中に何かが溜まってしまうのかもしれません
when you get old
あなたが年をとるとき
It starts producing a change like this
このような変化を生み出し始めます
Of course, the reason is still hard to say
もちろん、その理由はまだわかりません
But what I want to tell you today is
でも、今日私が皆さんに伝えたいのは、
One of these genes is called LORK2
これらの遺伝子の 1 つは LORK2 と呼ばれます
It also has this gene in the state run
この遺伝子は州の運営にもあります
This gene is actually
実はこの遺伝子は、
Most commonly found in Parkinson's municipalities
パーキンソン病の自治体で最もよく見られる
a gene with a mutation
突然変異のある遺伝子
Call it Pog8 or call it LORK2
Pog8 または LORK2 と呼んでください
We all have to be called LORK in the state.
私たちは皆、この州ではLORKと呼ばれなければなりません。
it has a protein
タンパク質が入っている
There are many functional regions on the protein, like this
タンパク質にはこのように機能領域がたくさんあります。
several areas
いくつかの地域
everyone can see
誰もが見ることができます
Then there are many different places on it
そうすると、いろいろなところにあるのですが、
can mutate
変異する可能性がある
We know that our chromosomes come in pairs
私たちは染色体が対になっていることを知っています
But as long as you have one of the chromosomes
でも染色体が1本あれば
A gene on LRK2
LRK2 上の遺伝子
If a mutation occurs
突然変異が起こったら
Then you add this
次に、これを追加します
The chances of getting Parkinson's become very, very high.
パーキンソン病になる可能性が非常に高くなります。
There is one of the most famous mutation points
最も有名な突然変異点の 1 つがあります。
called G2019S
G2019Sと呼ばれる
Everyone can remember this
これなら誰でも覚えられる
Call G2019S
G2019S を呼び出す
This is the most commonly found mutation
これは最も一般的に見られる変異です
Then its this feature
それからこの機能です
The characteristics of this mutation
この変異の特徴は
It's a very typical Parkinson's
まさに典型的なパーキンソン病です
Then he made the protein very active
それから彼はタンパク質を非常に活性化させました
Then they found out that in some of the Jews
そこで彼らは、ユダヤ人の中には次のようなことがわかった。
Or some North African Jewish arts
あるいは北アフリカのユダヤ芸術
The chances are very, very high
可能性は非常に高いです
The probability of this G2019S happening is very high
このG2019Sが起こる確率は非常に高い
Then if you go to Google
次に、Google にアクセスすると、
you can find this person
この人を見つけることができます
this very important person
このとても大切な人
very important to the world
世界にとって非常に重要な
A person with a major impact, he also got this G2019S mutant
大きな影響力を持つ人物、彼もこのG2019S変異体を手に入れた
a co-founder of Google
Googleの共同創設者
Say Brin
セイ・ブリン
his story is interesting
彼の話は面白いです
He was around 2006
彼は2006年頃でした
he discovered early
彼は早くに発見した
Discovered around 2000
2000年頃に発見
His mom has Parkinson's
彼の母親はパーキンソン病を患っています
Then he always felt that it was the influence of the environment
それから彼はそれが環境の影響であると常に感じていました
It's not genetics, it's environmental influences
遺伝じゃなくて環境の影響だよ
He felt that people with Parkinson's also understood environmental factors at that time
当時、パーキンソン病患者も環境要因を理解していると彼は感じた
and then at 20...because he makes a lot of money
そして20歳のとき...彼はたくさんお金を稼いでいるから
Got Google right?
Googleはわかりますか？
He imagined that the money was a lot
彼はお金がたくさんあると想像した
he took a wife
彼は妻をめとった
This lady is a student of biology
この女性は生物学の学生です
in our field
私たちの分野で
Then he pays his wife
それから彼は妻にお金を払います
to start a company
会社を設立する
Some people should have heard of this company called 23andMe
23andMe という会社のことを聞いたことがある人もいるはずです。
the sequence that can sequence your DNA
DNAを配列できる配列
sequence the DNA
DNAの配列を決定する
He gave his wife money and started a company like this
彼は妻にお金を与えてこのような会社を設立しました
Maybe it was a girl back then...
もしかしたらあの時は女の子だったかもしれない…
Then he also said to sequence your DNA
それから彼はあなたのDNAを配列決定するようにも言いました
he said yes
彼はそうだと言った
He sequenced his DNA
彼は自分のDNAを配列した
After the sequence is finished, let's see if we want to take a look
シーケンスが終了したら、見てみましょう
Is there any mutation?
突然変異はありますか？
He said okay come and see
彼は「分かった、見に来て」と言った
Let's say you really have the G2019S mutation
あなたが本当に G2019S 変異を持っているとしましょう
This is really a bit of this exciting
これは本当にちょっとエキサイティングなことだよ
But I think you can go to that blog to see this
しかし、これを見るにはそのブログにアクセスできると思います
he speaks very well
彼はとても上手に話します
He said that he actually thinks he is luckier than everyone else.
実際、自分は他の誰よりも幸運だと思っていたと彼は語った。
Because he thinks that when people get old
なぜなら彼は、人は年を取るとそう考えているからです。
always die of a disease
必ず病気で死ぬ
don't know what disease
何の病気か分かりません
It's not cancer, it's Alzheimer's disease
それは癌ではありません、アルツハイマー病です
Then he was lucky at such a young age
彼はそのような若さで幸運だった
in your 30s
30代で
You can know what diseases you will get when you get old
年を取るとどんな病気になるか分かる
so he can start now
だから彼は今すぐ始められる
Prevention of Parkinson's as a whole
パーキンソン病全体の予防
let him happen later
彼には後でさせてください
or reduce the chances of him happening
あるいは彼がそうなる可能性を減らす
or how like this
またはこのように
That's just the mutation of G2019S
それは G2019S の突然変異です
actually full
実際にはいっぱいです
pretty bad mutation
悪い突然変異
The probability of being called Parkinson's is very high
パーキンソン病と呼ばれる可能性が非常に高い
very high
非常高
So for him it is
だから彼にとってそれは
A lot of the money he earned has been used to do research on fear of mental evidence
彼が稼いだお金の多くは、精神的証拠に対する恐怖に関する研究に使われてきた
study like this
こうやって勉強する
Our laboratory also did a little bit of the effect of the G2019S mutation on the rapid burst
私たちの研究室では、G2019S 変異がラピッドバーストに及ぼす影響についても少し調べました。
You can see that this is the growth of a normal nerve cell
これは正常な神経細胞の成長であることがわかります。
very healthy very good
とても健康 とても良い
However, if the G2019S mutation is expressed
ただし、G2019S変異が発現している場合は、
Sutu grows sparser than the Sutu here
ここのスツよりもスツはまばらに生えています
much less, much shorter
はるかに少ない、はるかに短い
Then it's pretty sparse
それからかなりまばらです
So it's a pretty bad mutation
つまり、それはかなり悪い突然変異です
In human beings, fear of mental evidence will actually lead to a decrease in excess
人間の場合、精神的な証拠に対する恐怖は実際に過剰な行動の減少につながります。
This dohagan is a neurotransmitter
このドハガンは神経伝達物質です
Then in our highlight from bad to bad
それでは、悪いものから悪いものまでのハイライトで
Then Feimi this multi-octagan
それからフェイミはこのマルチオクタガン
Send this speed and receive it to the next nerve cell like this
この速度を送信して受信し、次の神経細胞に渡します。
Then the second is to say
次に、2番目はこう言います
This neuron that secretes this dopamine
このドーパミンを分泌するニューロン
Nerve cells also become very few
神経細胞も非常に少なくなります
from this normal to this
普通のこの状態からこれまで
This one has Parkinston's this black
これはパーキンストン病です
This one representing this dopamine neuron is gone.
このドーパミンニューロンを表すものは消えています。
gone
消えた
Then we can also see this experiment in Chinese
この実験は中国語でも見ることができます
Did you see that we are in Chinese
私たちが中国語で話しているのを見ましたか？
Then we can dye these many dopamine nerves
そうすれば、これらの多くのドーパミン神経を染めることができます
Then if express G2019S
じゃあエクスプレスG2019Sなら
This neuron also decreases
この神経細胞も減少します
And it is decreasing with time
そしてそれは時間の経過とともに減少しています
decrease over time
時間の経過とともに減少する
just like people
人と同じように
Then there are problems with these sure movements
そして、これらの確実な動きには問題があります
worse
悪い
Then
それから
so
それで
In fact, it can be used to imitate this
実はこれを真似するのにも使えます
A model of such a study by Parkinston
パーキンストンによるそのような研究のモデル
that here
それがここにある
This is Dr. Lin in our laboratory
私たちの研究室のリン博士です
He did a very interesting experiment
彼はとても興味深い実験をしました
he just said ok then
そのとき彼はただオーケーと言いました
It is said that this speed can be used as a model to study the Parkinson's reproductive disease of G2019S
この速度は、G2019Sのパーキンソン病の生殖器疾患を研究するモデルとして利用できると言われています
Then is there any antidote that can be found?
では、解毒剤は見つかるのでしょうか？
Then we know the US FDA US Food and Drug Administration
それから私たちは米国FDA米国食品医薬品局を知っています
They've probably approved maybe a thousand drugs so far.
彼らはおそらくこれまでに約千種類の薬を承認している
This drug can treat various diseases in the human body
この薬は人体のさまざまな病気を治療することができます
Then these drugs are probably harmless to the body.
そうすれば、これらの薬はおそらく体に無害です。
There is a little cure for a certain disease, there are some more or less curative functions like this
ある病気にはちょっとした治療法がある、多かれ少なかれこのような治療機能がある
Since these drugs are harmless to the human body, he asked
これらの薬は人体に無害なので、彼は尋ねました
Do these drugs have any effect on Parkinson's reproductive disease caused by G2019S?
これらの薬剤は、G2019S によって引き起こされるパーキンソン病の生殖器疾患に効果がありますか?
Has a positive protective or positive lifting or healing effect
積極的な保護効果、または積極的なリフティング効果または治癒効果がある
Then this experiment is unlikely to be done in humans or mice
となると、この実験は人間やマウスで行われる可能性は低い
For this person, you need about a thousand kinds of medicines, how many people will it take to test it out, right?
この人の場合、約1000種類の薬が必要ですが、それを調べるのに何人くらいかかりますか？
the mouse even if the mouse does
たとえマウスがそうなっても
also very very expensive
也非常非常貴
Rats just have to do one drug experiment
ラットは薬物実験を 1 回行うだけで済みます
maybe a lot of money
たぶん大金
But in Drosophila
しかしショウジョウバエでは
very simple
とてもシンプルな
a laboratory
実験室
a summer vacation
夏休み
An experiment that can probably be done
できそうな実験
so
それで
we'll do it with fruit flies
ショウジョウバエでやります
cheap and fast
安くて早い
So he took this fruit fly
そこで彼はこのショウジョウバエを捕まえました
look at its speed
そのスピードを見てください
this normal
この普通の
Then this is the expression of G2019S
それではG2019Sの表情です
That's in the 1000 drugs
それは1000種類の薬に含まれます
just found out say 1 2 3 4
たった今見つけた 1 2 3 4 と言う
There are 4 medicines in total
薬は全部で4種類あります
And let the speed go back up again
そしてまたスピードを上げていきましょう
speed up again
再びスピードを上げる
You saw that the speed increase is not bad
速度の増加は悪くないことがわかりました
that seems to shadow
それは影のように見える
Talk about not doing well for G2019S
G2019Sがうまくいかなかったという話
The cause of the boogie is that there is a
ブギーの原因は、
The role of compensation
補償の役割
or one is one
あるいは一つは一つだ
Then he took one of the medicines
それから彼は薬の一つを飲みました
This Lobar Stating
このローバーのステートメント
do one more research
もう一つ研究してください
Drosophila
ショウジョウバエ
I had a problem with exercise
運動に問題があった
It can also make it run a bit better
動作が少し良くなる可能性もあります
and then make it
そしてそれを作ります
The ability to exercise becomes stronger, like this
運動能力はこうやって強くなる
many people may know
多くの人が知っているかもしれません
What is Lobar Stating?
ローバーステートメントとは何ですか?
right
右
Stating this medicine
この薬を記載する
this this steroids
これはステロイド
this antilipidemic
この高脂血症薬
then let you this
それならこれをさせてください
Then
それから
Its paper was published in 2016
その論文は2016年に出版されました
Probably published at the beginning of the year like this
おそらく今年の初めにこんな感じで出版されたと思います
Then at the end of 2015
そして2015年末に
There is a clinical trial in the UK
イギリスでは臨床試験が行われている
They used a similar one of a Stating
彼らは同様のステートメントを使用しました
The drug is called Symbostating
その薬はシンボステーティングと呼ばれます
It is a relatively able to penetrate this
これは比較的貫通できる
This drug for the brain-blood barrier
脳血液関門の薬です
it can
できる
because this treats this
これはこれを扱うからです
Cholesterol probably doesn't need to get into the brain
コレステロールはおそらく脳に入る必要はない
But this Symbostating can enter the brain more easily
しかし、このシンボステーティングはより簡単に脳に入り込むことができます
They just experimented and said we're going to try this medicine
彼らはちょうど実験をして、この薬を試してみると言いました
Does it have a protective effect on Parkinson's life?
パーキンソン病の生命を守る効果はありますか?
that this is not to say
これは言うことではありません
that is
あれは
Well, sure enough research seems to
まあ、確かに十分な研究があるようですが、
actually quite effective
実際に非常に効果的です
And these medicines are safe medicines
そしてこれらの薬は安全な薬です
so you say
だからあなたは言う
Can this be used directly for human experiments?
これはそのまま人体実験に使用できるのでしょうか？
So what I'm going to say is
それで、私が言いたいのは、
Hey this
おい、これ
Seems like a nice tool indeed
確かに素晴らしいツールのようです
can be used to make a very simple
非常に単純なものを作るために使用できます
A process of early drug screening
早期薬物スクリーニングのプロセス
that seems to work
それはうまくいくようです
Maybe after the whole five years, there should be two or three years left
もしかしたら丸5年経ってもあと2、3年はあるはずだ
Let's see how they fare
彼らがどうやってやるか見てみましょう
Then use this research, then use it to do research is actually very special
そして、この研究を使用して、それを使用して研究を行うことは、実際には非常に特別です
In fact, no one believes that our algal medicines can have any effect on Parkinson's
実際、当社の藻類医薬品がパーキンソン病に効果があるとは誰も信じていません。
But for the sheer joy of research, quite a few students want to experiment like this
しかし、研究の純粋な楽しみのために、かなりの数の学生がこのような実験をしたいと考えています
Another student, he is in a department of food nutrition
もう一人の学生は食物栄養学科に所属しています
He said that their laboratory is dedicated to studying the protective effect of Tianma on human nerves.
同氏は、彼らの研究室は人間の神経に対する天麻の保護効果の研究に専念していると述べた。
They want to see fruit camps, Parkinson's-style fruit camps
彼らはフルーツキャンプ、パーキンソン病スタイルのフルーツキャンプを見たいのです
See if there is a protective effect
保護効果があるかどうかを確認してください
Traditionally we know traditional Chinese medicine
私たちは伝統的に伝統的な中国医学を知っています
In fact, this is what people have used for thousands of years, and it is harmless to the human body.
実際、これは人々が何千年もの間使用してきたものであり、人体には無害です。
And it has some protective effect
そしてそれはある程度の保護効果を持っています
It's just how to protect it
それをどうやって守るかだけだ
or to protect some kind of disease
あるいはある種の病気を防ぐため
Now medical progress should be defined more clearly
医療の進歩はより明確に定義されるべきです
Then can we repeat some experiments to see
それで、いくつかの実験を繰り返して確認できますか
is this pegasus
これはペガサスですか
have this effect
この効果がある
In fact, the tradition used to be a lot like
実際、この伝統はかつては次の​​ようなものでした。
hypocrites
偽善者
he said early on
彼は早い段階でこう言った
He also said that the food
彼は食べ物についても言いました
is your medicine
あなたの薬です
let medicine be your food
薬をあなたの食べ物にしましょう
That's actually what we call the homology of the history of medicine in Chinese.
それは実際、中国語の医学の歴史の相同性と呼ばれるものです。
Then you have heard many stories about Li Qingyun
それでは、李清雲についての多くの話を聞いたことがあるでしょう
I don't know if that is true or not
それが本当かどうかはわかりません
But you can Google it
でもグーグルで調べればわかるよ
Claimed to be born in the Qianlong period of the Qing Dynasty
清の乾隆時代に生まれたとされる
that lived until the Republic of China
中華民国まで生きていた
This one person in 20 years
この人は20年に1人
Also reported in the New York Times
ニューヨークタイムズでも報道されました
Also reported on the Washington Post
ワシントンポストでも報道されました
But to be honest, no one
でも正直に言うと誰もいない
can fully prove it
それを完全に証明できる
However, when he was interviewed
しかし、彼がインタビューを受けたとき、
When interviewed during the Republic of China, he said
中華民国時代にインタビューを受けた際、彼はこう語った。
He uses Chinese medicine as his
彼は漢方薬を自分の治療法として使用しています
this food looks like this
この食べ物はこんな感じです
A concept of homology in the history of medicine looks like this
医学の歴史における相同性の概念は次のようになります
So let's take a look
それでは見てみましょう
this right
これは正しい
Does Tianma have any protective effect on Parkinson's?
Tianmaにはパーキンソン病を予防する効果がありますか?
Well, it's very clear for everyone to see this.
実際、これは誰の目にも明らかです。
This experiment is actually very simple
この実験は実はとても簡単です
Then we also found some high school students to do the experiment
それから、実験をする高校生も見つけました。
You'll see it says this is a control group experiment
これは対照群の実験であると表示されていることがわかります
This is what G2019S just said
G2019S が今言ったことです
Then what we want is that the fruit fly can climb over this 8 cm line
次に、私たちが望むのは、ショウジョウバエがこの 8 cm のラインを乗り越えられることです。
So we knock the flies down to the very bottom
だから私たちはハエを一番下までたたき落とします
See how many fruit flies can climb 8 cm in one time
一度に何匹のショウジョウバエが8cm登ることができるか見てみましょう
Let's just videotape and see how many go by
ビデオを撮って何人が通り過ぎるか見てみましょう
Then you can see that when the G2019S mutation is said
G2019S 変異と言われると、次のことがわかります。
Lots of fruit flies just stay down there
たくさんのショウジョウバエがそこに留まっている
It doesn't pass too much, and it doesn't move too much.
通り過ぎず、動き過ぎず。
Only two or three have climbed here
ここに登ったのは二人か三人だけ
only three passed
合格したのは3人だけ
Most of the others are below
他のほとんどは以下にあります
Can't go up
上がれない
There are quite a few more in the control group
対照群にはさらにかなりの数がいます
So we fed it different doses of this pegasus in the fruit fly
そこで、ショウジョウバエにこのペガサスをさまざまな量で与えました。
0.1% 0.5% 1.0% of the time
0.1% 0.5% 1.0% の確率で
you see say
ほら言うね
This same G2019
これと同じ G2019
Some really started to climb well.
本当に上手に登り始めた人もいました。
Climbing well is more than 8 cm line
登り上手は8cmライン以上
Then we can see that the statistics here also say the same.
そうすれば、ここでの統計も同じことを示していることがわかります。
To pegasus when we can see say
見えるときはペガサスに言う
It actually has an effect
実際に効果はありますよ
Can make it climb over 8 cm
8cm以上登ることができる
That is to say, to restore its athletic ability
つまり、運動能力を回復するということです。
Then let's look at the growth of speed
次に速度の伸びを見てみましょう
The speed of growth has also returned to this way
成長スピードもこのように戻ってきました
this is an experiment
これは実験です
And it is really Parchment
そしてそれは本当に羊皮紙です
So there is nothing to tell you here
したがって、ここでお伝えすることは何もありません
But don't try too casually.
ただし、あまり気軽に試しすぎないでください。
However, traditional Chinese medicine of Tianma
しかし、天馬の伝統的な漢方薬は
It manufactures that it is essential for the blood circulation of the brain
脳の血液循環に不可欠であることを製造します
or everything is very good
またはすべてがとても良い
The memory is very good like this
このように記憶力は非常に良いです
then we just want to say to study
それなら勉強してくださいと言いたいだけです
Because there are some chemical components in Tianma
ペガサスには化学成分が含まれているため、
The most important thing is a component called Gastroding
最も重要なのはGastrodingと呼ばれるコンポーネントです
Then we want to say look at these chemical molecules
次に、これらの化学分子を見てくださいと言いたいのです。
Or because traditional Chinese medicine is a rich prescription
あるいは漢方薬は豊富な処方だから
often several
多くの場合、複数の
Then we want to try to see which ones are added to which ones.
次に、どれがどれに追加されるかを確認してみたいと思います。
that has a better effect
その方が良い効果がある
At the same time, we also want to see
同時に私たちも見たいのです
how did it come about
それはどのようにして起こったのか
suppress this
これを抑制する
Parkinson's called this
パーキンソン病はこれをこう呼びます
The effect is like this
効果はこんな感じ
at the cellular level
細胞レベルで
What the hell is it doing to the cells
いったい細胞に何をしているのでしょうか
Then this really reminds everyone
それから、これは本当に皆さんに思い出させます
Because we have different models in the fruit camp
フルーツキャンプには色々なモデルがあるので
Parkinson's name
パーキンソン病の名前
Another Parkinson's
もう一つのパーキンソン病
another model
別のモデル
it doesn't work at all
まったく機能しません
that this is very special
これはとても特別なことだということ
we feel
私達は感じる
Maybe this Pegasus is for a certain type of Parkinson's
おそらくこのペガサスは、ある種のパーキンソン病のためのものでしょう
only effective
効果的なだけ
For some classes, it is not necessarily the effect
一部のクラスでは必ずしも効果が得られるわけではありません
Now let's talk about precision medicine
次に、精密医療について話しましょう
we need to know
私たちは知る必要がある
If you have Parkinson's
パーキンソン病がある場合
What kind of mutation
どのような突然変異ですか
let you get this certificate
この証明書を取得させてください
then sick
それから病気
Then what special
それでは、特別なことは何ですか
probably everyone
おそらく全員
The way to treat is different
治療法が違う
So we wish to say
そこで私たちが言いたいのは、
our research on this
これに関する私たちの研究
theoretically
理論的には
Parkinson's theory
パーキンソン病理論
There are some contributions like this
こんな寄稿もあります
so i see my time is about
だから私の時間はもう終わりだ
So finally I want to thank the lab
最後に研究室に感謝したいと思います
former student
元生徒
and postdoctoral
そしてポスドク
this is us
これが私たちです
When we got together a few years ago, we took a big group photo like this
数年前に集まったとき、こんな大きな集合写真を撮りました
Then this is many former students
それから、これは多くの元生徒たちです
Here's what it looks like back with a postdoctoral fellow
ポスドク研究員との様子は次のとおりです
And now there are still many students in the laboratory
そして今、研究室にはまだたくさんの学生がいます
Taken before Chinese New Year this year
今年の旧正月前に撮影
Everyone is wearing red clothes
みんな赤い服を着ています
The Year of the Golden River Dog in Western Ocean looks like this
西洋のゴールデンリバードッグ年はこんな感じ
I won't list them all because there are too many names.
名前が多すぎるので全部は載せません。
Then we have many collaborators
それから、たくさんの協力者がいます
Like this at home and abroad
国内外でもこんな感じ
So I'm just reporting here
なのでここで報告するだけです
And thank you all for listening
そして聞いてくれた皆さんありがとう
Thank you, Mr. Jane, for your wonderful speech.
ジェーンさん、素晴らしいスピーチをありがとうございました。
From his research using Drosophila from the basis of neurodevelopment
神経発達の基礎からショウジョウバエを使った研究から
to disease research
病気の研究へ
find drugs that might work
効きそうな薬を見つける
let's wait
待とう
Open to everyone to ask questions
誰でも気軽に質問できる
We will give a prize and a small gift to the top ten
上位10名には賞品とささやかなプレゼントを差し上げます
This is the 90th anniversary of the Central Plains
今年はセントラルプレーンズ90周年です
It is a coaster for our 1992 anniversary celebration this year
今年の1992年記念コースターです
Also before you ask
また、質問する前に
Let me first announce that our next month is December
まず来月は 12 月であることをお知らせします
December 25th
12月25日
Our feast of knowledge is served by our
私たちの知識の饗宴は、私たちの
Researcher Peng Xiaoyan, Institute of Chinese Culture and Philosophy
中国文化哲学研究所 研究員 彭暁燕
he gave the lecture
彼は講義をした
assassin
刺客
Evil food
邪悪な食べ物
This is a movie by Hou Hsiao-hsien
これは侯孝賢の映画です
His answer is Hou Hsiao-hsien's Tang China
彼の答えは侯孝賢の「唐」です
welcome everybody
みなさん、ようこそ
Come to listen to the lecture next month
来月は講演を聞きに来てください
then we're open right now
じゃあ今は開いてるよ
ask questions
質問をする
then our online friends
それからオンラインの友達
You can also send us questions through that Facebook
Facebook を通じて質問をお送りいただくこともできます
Let's give priority to asking questions on the spot
この生の質疑を優先しましょう
please
お願いします
sure enough larvae
案の定幼虫
where are you
どこにいるの
it's not that active
それほど活発ではありません
But when its foot starvation is that one
しかし、その足が飢えているときは、
it is very active
とても活発です
But with the G2019S on this side
しかし、こちら側のG2019Sでは
It is relatively inactive
比較的活動的ではありません
is there any difference
違いはありますか
or something different
または何か違うもの
or because it lacks food
あるいは食べ物が足りないから
but it is normal
でもそれが普通です
But because of lack of food
しかし食糧不足のせいで
is to let it driving force
それを原動力にすることです
always looking for food
いつも食べ物を探している
But it has no energy
でもエネルギーがない
so i understand
だから分かりました
Thank you
ありがとう
wow you
すごいね
You looked at my picture carefully.
あなたは私の写真を注意深く見てくれました。
I deliberately avoided talking
意図的に話すことを避けた
still noticed by you
まだあなたに気づかれて
that just now that foot supply
それはちょうど今その足の供給
That is an experimental condition
それは実験条件です
An Experimental Situation
実験的な状況
Because we thought of two ways
2つの方法を考えたので
make fruit flies crawl faster
ショウジョウバエの這いを速くする
I can never tell fruit flies
ショウジョウバエとは決して言えません
you climb faster
あなたはより速く登ります
So there are two ways
したがって、2つの方法があります
One is to increase the temperature a little bit
一つは温度を少し上げることです
At this time, fruit flies move
この時期、ショウジョウバエが動きます
just faster
ただ速く
that's what we worry about
それが私たちが心配していることです
Results of our experiments
実験結果
You want to say that it is because of the influence of temperature
気温の影響だと言いたいのかな
rather than a crawling issue
クロールの問題ではなく
So we have another situation
それで、別の状況があります
That means leaving the flies without food
それはハエに餌を与えずに放置することを意味します
this one with food
これは食べ物と一緒です
then you think it's easy
それなら簡単だと思うよ
There is food to move
動く食べ物がある
just hide in the food
食べ物の中に隠れるだけ
Started going out to find food when there was no food
食べ物がないときに食べ物を探しに出かけるようになった
what are you doing
あなたは何をしている
So the one without food really started crawling around
それで、食べ物のない人は本当に這い始めました
looking for food like this
このような食べ物を探しています
So the case of our two different experiments
2 つの異なる実験の場合
then come
それから来てください
This is exactly the same as ever
これは今までとまったく同じです
just the situation
ちょうどその状況
The conditions of the experiment are different
実験条件が違う
See what it looks like with that prominent growth
顕著な成長がどのように見えるかを見てください
So that's a set of experiments
これは一連の実験です
What about this group of experiments
この実験グループについてはどうでしょうか
It's really all for the baby.
それは本当にすべて赤ちゃんのためです。
is in the same food
同じ食べ物に入っている
just have a food with pegasus
ペガサスと一緒に食事をするだけです
Pegasus in a food
食べ物の中のペガサス
when we're just doing experiments
ただ実験をしているとき
Just take it to the empty pipe and do it
空のパイプに持って行ってやってください
It used to eat the baby like this
昔はこうやって赤ちゃんを食べてたんだ
good
良い
ask that
それを尋ねてください
Or want to send some islands
またはいくつかの島を送りたい
That batch really
そのバッチは本当に
Those two batches really
それらの 2 つのバッチは本当に
They are all LOMO
それらはすべてLOMOです
There is no such G2019S
そんなG2019Sはない
yes
はい
Thank you
ありがとう
Excuse me
すみません
that generally speaking
一般的に言えば
Crabpena
クラブペナ
Why does it go along the nerve
なぜ神経に沿って伝わるのか
Is it related to the protrusion of the nerve?
神経の突出と関係があるのでしょうか？
I didn't hear the first sentence
最初の一文が聞き取れなかった
Is there any snake skin that people talk about?
人々が話題にしているヘビ皮はありますか?
snake skin is an allergy
蛇皮はアレルギーです
I think it's a foam pillow
発泡枕だと思います
Yes, it's an immune system problem
はい、免疫系の問題です
Does that have anything to do with the nervous system?
それは神経系と何か関係がありますか？
that's a good question
それは良い質問です
But our neural network
しかし、私たちのニューラルネットワークは、
in the body that nerve
体のその神経では
Zhou Tu Sutu actually looks very good
Zhou Tu Sutu は実際にとても良く見えます
If I hadn't suddenly shown you
突然見せなかったら
In fact, the underlying dissatisfaction with this nerve
実はこの神経の根底にある不満は、
This, Zhoutu and Sutu
これ、周都と蘇都
so yes
あ、はい
I don't think so
私はそうは思わない
I don't know if it's related, sorry
関係あるか分かりません、ごめんなさい
a hello
こんにちは
What I want to ask is that just now
私が聞きたいのは今のことです
That's what Dr. Jane mentioned
それがジェーン博士が言ったことです
it's fast
これは速い
he will just follow
彼はただ従うだけだ
Epidermal cells have interactions between
表皮細胞は相互作用を持っています。
I'm more curious about
もっと興味があるのは
When the epidermal cells eat up the tree soil one by one
表皮細胞が木の土を一つ一つ食べていくと
Where is it to make it break
どこで壊れるのか
Is it a weaker place or where it breaks off?
弱いところなのか、折れたところなのか？
this is a good question
これは良い質問です
How to cut it off is arbitrary
切り方は任意
But it seems to be broken section by section
しかし、セクションごとに壊れているようです
The process of breaking it is actually quite special.
それを壊すプロセスは実際には非常に特殊です。
that is to say every
つまりすべての
In fact, this can show a phenomenon of neurodegeneration
実際、これは神経変性の現象を示す可能性があります。
When the nerve degenerates, this tree soil or axis soil
神経が変性すると、この木土や軸土が
When broken, there are two forms
壊れると2つの形になる
One we call Dying back
私たちがダイイング・バックと呼ぶもの
That is to say, it starts from the tail of the stomach and dies to the body of the cell.
つまり、胃の尾部から始まり、細胞の本体まで死んでいきます。
section by section is broken
セクションごとに壊れています
When these two places are already injured
すでにこの二か所が傷ついている場合
After your side is broken, its tree soil or shaft soil is useless
あなたの側面が壊れた後、その木の土やシャフトの土は役に立ちません
It started to die all the way to the body
体まで死に始めた
The other is like this, a pretty uniform one, and everyone cuts it off at the same time.
もう一つはこんな感じで、かなり均一なもので、全員が同時に切ります。
The model I just mentioned is the second model, which means that it is actually quite uniform
先ほど述べたモデルは 2 番目のモデルであり、実際には非常に均一であることを意味します。
start everywhere
どこからでも始められる
the process is to say
プロセスは言うことです
It is very special, in fact, it is a very special model, that is to say, it is close to the cell body at the beginning
それは非常に特別です、実際、それは非常に特別なモデルです、つまり、最初は細胞体に近いです
will be cut first
最初に切られます
How to cut this knife, in fact, is now a very important one in this field in the study of people
実際、このナイフの切り方は、人間の研究においてこの分野で非常に重要になっています。
The second is the knife, once it touches the body
2つ目はナイフ、体に触れたら
after leaving
去った後
It starts to get empty inside, some of it
内側が空になり始める、その一部
If you're a biology student, something called microtubules will start
生物学を勉強すると微小管というものが始まります
break off, and then it's
中断して、それから
The membrane on the surface will start to have some
表面の膜に多少の汚れがつき始めます。
Start with a pig, pig, pig, see what you see
豚、豚、豚から始めて、何が見えるかを見てください
pig pig pig pig, then
豚豚豚豚、それでは
At this moment
この瞬間に
This epidermal cell will give it
この表皮細胞が与えてくれるのです
Recycle like this, eat it up and recycle like this
こうやってリサイクルして、食べてこうやってリサイクルする
As for which side is recycled first and which side is later, it is actually still under study.
どちらが先にリサイクルされ、どちらが後にリサイクルされるかについては、実はまだ研究中です。
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
The teacher just talked about this
先生がちょうどこのことについて話しました
London's taxi driver's hippocampus
ロンドンのタクシー運転手の海馬
i think it's very interesting
とても興味深いと思います
the problem is
問題は
it got bigger and smaller
大きくなったり小さくなったり
This process is because its cell body itself becomes larger
この過程は細胞体自体が大きくなるからです
or more prominent
またはそれ以上に目立つ
Or the number of cells changed
またはセルの数が変更されました
then the second is
それから2番目は
When we were in college every time we hung out
私たちが大学にいたとき、私たちはいつも一緒にいた
That female classmate said
その同級生の女子生徒はこう言った。
You have a better sense of direction
あなたは方向感覚が良くなりました
you drive you ride
あなたは運転します、あなたは乗ります
I don't know if it's true or not
本当かどうかは分かりません
I don't know if there is any research
研究があるかどうかは知りませんが
Is there any difference between boys and girls?
男の子と女の子に違いはありますか？
I can't answer the second question
2番目の質問には答えられません
because there are a lot of women
女性が多いので
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
That
それか
actually i remember
実は覚えています
Grandson Mi's wife has a very good sense of direction
孫のミーさんの妻は非常に方向感覚が優れている
I remember as long as
覚えている限り
You tell her casually about a certain point in Taipei City
あなたは彼女に台北市のある場所について何気なく話しました
she can say right away
彼女はすぐに言うことができます
how to go how to go
どうやって行くか どうやって行くか
I can talk to you on the phone
電話で話せます
don't need this
これは必要ありません
and react immediately
そしてすぐに反応する
Netizens turn to the host to turn like this
ネチズンはホストに向かってこう言う
There will be a difference between men and women
男女の違いもあるだろうし
I can't answer what I've learned
学んだことには答えられない
what's the first question
最初の質問は何ですか
Why is it a change in nerve cells or a prominent change
なぜ神経細胞の変化や顕著な変化なのか
In fact, this question is also a very good question.
実際、この質問も非常に良い質問です。
Your question is on point
あなたの質問は的を射ています
it's not clear what's going on
何が起こっているのかは不明です
Because it looks like a group of functional images
機能的なイメージの集合体に見えるので
a large area
広いエリア
no way to see in depth
深く見る方法がない
A few nerve cells are not deep enough
いくつかの神経細胞の深さが不十分です
Not enough resolution
解像度が足りない
So I kind of want to jump over and tell him to stand out
だから私は飛び越えて彼に目立つように言いたいのです
It's actually the one that built the driver in London
実はこのドライバーをロンドンで作ったのがこれです
we didn't know that
私たちはそれを知りませんでした
I'm Lin Xiumei
私は林秀梅です
I've been in radiation oncology for 20 years
私は放射線腫瘍科に20年間携わっています
as an administrative assistant
管理アシスタントとして
So this IC bag and poo are very interested
ということでこのICバッグとうんちがとても気になります
After leaving the hospital in 1993, I did community visits
1993年に病院を退院した後、私は地域訪問をしました。
So now the election is over
さて、選挙は終わりました
That referendum, not the gender identity part
その国民投票は性自認の部分ではない
Because today's focus is that this gene is expressed during the mating period
なぜなら、今日の焦点は、この遺伝子が発情期に発現するということだからです。
that has already decided his fate
それはすでに彼の運命を決めている
So is this gender orientation determined at birth?
では、この性的指向は出生時に決まるのでしょうか？
Because while I'm doing community visits
コミュニティ訪問をしているときに
I also met mommy mommy gay women
ママママのゲイの女性にも会ったよ
Going to that foreign country to learn Buddhist scriptures and raising children
その異国に仏典を学びに行き、子育てをする
They are very serious and well prepared to do this
彼らは非常に真剣で、これを行う準備が十分に整っています
That's doing NHS long-term follow-up of teenagers
それはNHSによる十代の若者たちの長期追跡調査だ
There is also a little boy who wanted to be a girl since elementary school
小学生の頃から女の子になりたかった男の子もいます
I'm totally a long-term visit
完全に長期滞在です
Elementary school, middle school and high school to his university to serve in the army
小学校、中学校、高校と大学に進み、兵役に就く
That's for sure he wants to be a girl
それは確かに彼は女の子になりたいです
So he works part-time to make money during this process
そのため、彼はその過程でお金を稼ぐためにパートタイムで働きます。
And then by the time I'm done visiting he's actually headed south
そして、私が訪問を終える頃には、彼は実際に南へ向かっています
So because I'm all my own case
だから私はすべて私自身のケースだから
So I am very acceptable to this gender orientation
したがって、私はこの性的指向を非常に受け入れます
But why is this turbulent referendum so chaotic
しかし、なぜこの混乱に満ちた住民投票はこれほど混乱しているのでしょうか
Thanks
ありがとう
I can't give any comments on the part of the referendum
住民投票についてはコメントできない
I think if it's just creatures, most of them are hermaphrodites.
生き物だけなら雌雄同体がほとんどだと思います。
You evolved to say male or female it's a
あなたは男性か女性か言うように進化しました
But there are many kinds of living things
でも、いろんな生き物がいる
OK, then we also know that there are more than one or seven birds
OK、では、鳥が 1 羽または 7 羽以上いることもわかります。
Many creatures also have childishness, even fish can change sex
多くの生き物には子供っぽさもあり、魚でも性転換することがある
Even in research there's something called parthenogenesis
研究でも単為生殖と呼ばれるものがあります
In terms of biology, it has a lot of diversity
生物学的には非常に多様性があります
That person has been difficult for us recently, and I don't know how to say it
あの人は最近私たちにとって苦手なのですが、なんと言えばいいのかわかりません
I also sympathize
私も同情します
Thank you
ありがとう
The last one and the one over here
最後のものと、ここにあるもの
Then after this one, then that one
それから、これの次、そしてあの次
hello professor i would like to ask
こんにちは、教授、聞きたいことがあります
Because in the past few days, it seems that there is a
というのも、ここ数日の間に、
Gene-edited babies
遺伝子編集された赤ちゃん
Then he said that he could exempt AIDS patients
それから彼はエイズ患者を免除できると言いました
So what do you think the professor thinks about this news?
それで、教授はこのニュースについてどう思いますか?
This thing must be wrong
このことは間違っているに違いない
It's about things, it's not that the news is wrong
それは物事に関することであり、ニュースが間違っているということではありません
something is wrong
何かが間違っている
Because any experiment on humans has to go through
人体実験は必ず通過しなければならないからです
Strictly because this is too risky
厳密に言えばリスクが高すぎるので
This is too risky. I think this person is for fame.
これは危険すぎる。この人は名声のためだと思う。
Because I heard that their technology
彼らの技術があると聞いたので、
Chris Pratt This technique
クリス・プラットのこのテクニック
In Hong Kong, it seems that a conference will be held in these two days
この二日間香港でカンファレンスが開催されるようです
he was one of the speakers
彼は講演者の一人でした
is that ahead of the news
それはニュースより先のことですか
just make a splash or something
スプラッシュか何かをするだけです
We feel that this kind of thing is ethical in this research
この研究ではこのようなことは倫理的であると感じます
we are to follow
私たちは従うべきです
It means following all the rules like this
このようにすべてのルールに従うことを意味します
Why do we need state-run operations? Because there are actually very few regulations on state-run operations
なぜ国営事業が必要なのかというと、実際には国営事業に対する規制がほとんどないからです。
How do we kill and harvest
どうやって殺し、収穫するのか
But being a mouse requires a lot of rules
しかし、ネズミになるには多くのルールが必要です
Then when it comes to people, I think this is almost what it should be
それから人間に関して言えば、これはほぼそうあるべきだと思います
I don't think it's advisable
それはお勧めできません
thank you professor
ありがとう教授
hello that professor i think
こんにちは、あの教授だと思います
that's me to that one just now
それは今のあの人にとって私です
It’s just that the devouring part is a bit brutal
ただ、食い込みの部分が少し残酷です
I'm very interested, and I want to ask if there is one just now
とても興味があるので、今あるのか聞きたいのですが
Is that the Flash movie?
あれはフラッシュムービーですか？
Then I want to ask him that
そこで彼に聞きたいのですが、
The mechanism of lightning is because
雷の仕組みとしては、
Did Membre Procuretio change so that caused him to flash like this?
メンブレ・プロキュレティオが変わったので、このように点滅したのでしょうか？
The first one is to use Eocasium's reporter
1つ目は、Eocasiumのレポーターを使用することです。
I think you probably learned this
おそらくこれを学んだのだと思います
Then they feel that Membrane has a potential change
そして、メンブレンには変化の可能性があると感じます。
So all of a sudden it's a little easier to activate
突然、アクティベートが少し簡単になりました
Suddenly
突然
In fact, it is more understandable why it looks like a lightning bolt.
実際、それが稲妻のように見える理由はより理解できます。
just light up instead of saying this everywhere
どこでも言う代わりに明るくしてください
do you know what i mean
分かりますか
why this one
なぜこれが
then down again
それからまた下りる
There is no certain order of which one comes first and which one comes after.
どちらが先でどちらが後になるという特定の順序はありません。
I know that in terms of a single one it is that one suddenly is
一つのことに関して言えば、それは突然あることだと私は知っています。
Because things outside the mold flow into that electric grid
型の外にあるものがその電力網に流れ込むからです
so changing their potential
だから彼らの可能性を変える
learn
学び
Thanks
ありがとう
ok i have two questions
わかりました、質問が 2 つあります
First, some people often dream
まず、よく夢を見る人がいます。
Make that teacher dream the same dream
あの先生にも同じ夢を見させて
He will eventually become his memory
やがて彼は彼の思い出になるだろう
That is to say, he will also be like that
つまり彼もそうなるだろう
As you said, some Synapse forms
あなたが言ったように、いくつかのシナプスフォーム
second question
2番目の質問
that's what i think
それが私が思うことです
It seems that Alzheimer's is almost as much as this Parkinson's
アルツハイマー病もこのパーキンソン病と同じくらいあるらしい
So I'm very interested in the Pegasus effect you found
だから私はあなたが見つけたペガサス効果にとても興味があります
Can it prevent PD? Or is it only effective through the BBB?
PD を予防できますか? それとも BBB を通じてのみ効果がありますか?
this is a good question
これは良い質問です
Will dreaming change the new nefs?
夢を見ることが新しいネフを変えるでしょうか？
I...
私...
should be
あるべきです
Don't talk about dreaming
夢については話さないでください
In fact, someone went to see the inside of these new nefs...
実際、誰かがこれらの新しいネフの内部を見に行きました...
ah sorry
ああ、ごめんなさい
Highlight the expression of the protein inside
内部のタンパク質の発現を強調表示する
In fact, day and night are very different
実際、昼と夜は全く違います
The outstanding structure, the outstanding composition looks like this
優れた構造、優れた構成はこんな感じ
then i want to dream
それなら夢を見たいです
sometimes you do remember
時々あなたは覚えています
then you can also take it as an experience
それを経験として捉えることもできます
it may make some changes to some prominence
一部の著名性に何らかの変化をもたらす可能性があります
i think it should be
そうあるべきだと思う
that looks like my daughter probably
それはおそらく私の娘に似ています
she dreamed she remembered
彼女は夢を見た、思い出した
She got up and told me what she did
彼女は立ち上がって、自分が何をしたか私に話しました
I probably don't even remember what dreams I had.
おそらくどんな夢を見たかも覚えていないでしょう。
I don't know where the difference is
どこが違うのか分かりません
Well, I probably haven't done enough research on dreams.
まあ、私は夢について十分に調べていないかもしれません。
The second question is that PD and ADO
2 番目の質問は、PD と ADO です。
In fact, Tianma is quite expensive.
実際、天馬はかなり高価です。
This stinky coincidence actually I think
この臭い偶然は実際のところ私は思う
Maybe we can change our lives and try today.
もしかしたら、私たちは人生を変えて今日試してみることができるかもしれません。
Maybe it will work
もしかしたらうまくいくかもしれない
take a what turmeric tree
何のウコンの木を取りますか
you can listen to a lot
たくさん聞くことができます
These are some of the protective effects on the human body
これらは人体に対する保護効果の一部です
Food or Chinese medicine like this
こんな食べ物や漢方薬
So I think from the point of view of protection and maintenance
保護とメンテナンスの観点から考えます
In fact, there are no shortcomings, that's all I can say
実際、欠点はない、それしか言えません
But if you think this can be treated
でも、これは治療できると思うなら
or what when i think
または私が考えているときは何ですか
Actually, I have an experiment I want to tell you about
実は、皆さんにお話ししたい実験があるのです
You might actually feel a little disappointed
実際には少しがっかりするかもしれません
Our fruit battalions are actually
私たちの果物大隊は実際には
We started feeding Pegasus to it as soon as it was born
生まれてすぐにペガサスを与え始めました
So let it grow strong and healthy from an early age
だから、小さい頃から強くて健康に育ってください
So let's try to say let it start
それでは始めましょうと言ってみましょう
When he is afraid of spiritual administration, let him feed the gods
霊的管理が怖いときは、神に食事を与えさせてください
that's not invalid
それは無効ではありません
Probably for a week
おそらく一週間くらい
that effect
その効果
Then a week later he started falling again
それから一週間後、彼は再び倒れ始めました
Started to look sick again
また具合が悪くなり始めた
So the effect is not like
したがって、効果はそうではありません
The effect of us being born and starting to feed
私たちが生まれ、食事を始めたことによる影響
that's why this gesture
だからこそこのジェスチャー
It can also be said that there are some effects
一定の効果があるとも言える
Then if you live in camp for 60 days
じゃあ60日間のフルーツキャンプなら
we figured it out
私たちはそれを理解しました
This week might be equal to seven human years.
今週は人間の 7 年に相当するかもしれません。
If the seven-year increase
7年間増加した場合
good exercise health
良い運動の健康
It's actually not bad
実際は悪くないよ
It's just whether our thing can
それは私たちのことができるかどうかだけです
transform it into a human
それを人間に変える
This is still to be studied
これはまだ研究の余地があります
Then we just want to say that it's okay for people
それなら、人々にとっては大丈夫だと言いたいだけです
Hello
こんにちは
thank you professor for your speech
教授のスピーチに感謝します
because there are two important messages
重要なメッセージが 2 つあるため、
I want to ask
聞きたいです
The first important message is to say
最初の重要なメッセージは次のとおりです
The evolutionary degeneration of this brain activation
この脳活性化の進化的変性
it has a protein pattern
タンパク質のパターンがある
No, that electropowder
いや、あのエレクトロパウダー
Electropowder pattern protein
電子粉末パターンタンパク質
it can control
それはコントロールできる
is it true
それは本当ですか
the second
二番目
This one is called expansion fish
これは拡張魚と呼ばれるものです
This dimensional creature
この次元生物は
it can transfer this memory
この記憶を転送できる
Can these two phenomena
この二つの現象はあり得るでしょうか
please explain
説明してください
Thanks
ありがとう
Yes, I don't quite understand the second question
はい、2 番目の質問がよくわかりません
Expansion fish
拡張魚
A kind of vitamin
ビタミンの一種
Seems
らしい
Its head looks like a snail
頭がカタツムリのように見えます
but it doesn't have that shell
しかし、その殻はありません
it is a mollusc
それは軟体動物です
Broadfish
ブロードフィッシュ
Applecia
アップルシア
what is the problem with applecia
アップルシアの問題は何ですか
that first question
最初の質問
Ebeta cumulative this is
エベタ累積これは
Inside Alzheimer's
アルツハイマー病の内部
one of the most common phenomena
最も一般的な現象の 1 つ
There's a lot of politics here
ここには政治がたくさんある
some say it's harmful
それは有害だと言う人もいます
that some say yes
ある人はそうだと言う
In fact, it is protective
実際、それは保護的です
Why because it means your nerve cells start
なぜかというと、神経細胞が動き始めるからです。
produces an accumulation of protein and then it
タンパク質の蓄積を生成し、
it actually pushes it outside where it accumulates
それは実際にそれを蓄積する場所の外に押し出します
That's a protective effect on nerve cells
それは神経細胞を保護する効果です
then many people
それから多くの人が
When they did that autopsy, they passed away.
彼らが解剖したとき、彼らは亡くなりました。
Although they have Alzheimer's disease
彼らはアルツハイマー病を患っているにもかかわらず、
It can be found that there are actually
実際にあることが分かります
The accumulation of this endoamylose, this Aβ
このエンドアミロースの蓄積、このAβ
What is this thing with
これは何でしょうか
Alzheimer's disease is now believed by many people
アルツハイマー病は現在多くの人に信じられています
But is it completely related?
しかし、それは完全に関係しているのでしょうか？
Everyone has a little bit of this problem
誰もが少しずつこの問題を抱えています
Then this has a great impact on the development of drugs
これは医薬品の開発に大きな影響を与えます
Because many people take this amyloid Aβ thing
多くの人がこのアミロイドAβのものを摂取しているからです
to be a target
ターゲットになる
Then he said that looking for medicine can prevent its aggregation like this
すると彼は、薬を探すことでこのように薬の集合を防ぐことができると言いました。
Then it will, you just asked that it will not spread, right?
そうすると、広がりますよ、今、広がりませんとおっしゃいましたよね。
It can control its evolutionary degradation
進化による劣化を制御できる
It needs this to control if it evolves
進化するかどうかを制御するにはこれが必要です
Maybe it's a matter of the quantity.
もしかしたら量の問題かもしれません。
it can add k and subtract
kを加算したり減算したりできます
can increase its
それを増やすことができます
to increase or decrease to increase
増やすか減らすか増やす
it reduces its function
それはその機能を低下させます
to control its function
その機能を制御するために
function
関数
It says it can solve this geriatric syndrome
この老人症候群を解決できるという
then i don't know it's true
それならそれが本当か分からない
Alzheimer's to the present
アルツハイマー病から現在まで
Seriously it's not the same
真剣にそれは同じではありません
Check this out online
これをオンラインでチェックしてください
There is indeed this thing
確かにこんな事あるんですね
That is to say, if the information
つまり、その情報があれば、
is possible
可能だ
no medicine yet sorry
薬はまだありません、ごめんなさい
as far as i know
私の知る限りでは
There is no effective medicine
有効な薬はない
This answer does not answer no problem
この回答は問題の解決にはなりません
We just say there is this message
このメッセージがあると言っているだけです
We know this thing
私たちはこのことを知っています
someone is working on this
誰かがこれに取り組んでいます
That is to say, the future
つまり、未来
Our old man's disease can be solved
私たちの老人の病気は解決できる
Alzheimer's disease is this
アルツハイマー病はこれです
This symptom can be resolved
この症状は解決できる
our health insurance
私たちの健康保険
It now has 2.8 million of this age
現在、この年齢層の人口は 280 万人です
Human life has been extending since it was opened
人類の寿命は開闢以来延び続けている
but this
しかしこれは
this human life
この人間の人生
What happened to him after the scene
現場の後、彼に何が起こったのか
That is to say, the old man has his own administration and the bearer
つまり、老人は自分の統治者とその担い手を持っているのです。
Will this rate of increase also increase?
この増加率もさらに高まるのでしょうか？
Is it that there will be social problems?
社会問題が起きるということでしょうか？
Let's solve this problem from this aspect
この問題をこの側面から解決しましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
people will be interesting
人は面白くなるだろう
Finally there will be a disease
ついに病気が発生する
The current parlance is to talk about healthy aging
現在の専門用語では、健康に老化することについて話します。
the one you had before you died
あなたが死ぬ前に持っていたもの
It is not healthy for Taiwan to average 9 to 10 years now
台湾の平均寿命は現在9～10年で不健全
there is a problem here
ここに問題があります
can i talk
話してもいいですか
Because Yang Zhiliang, Director of Health Yang Zhiliang said
なぜなら、保健部長の楊志良氏はこう言ったからです。
His goal
彼の目標
He is old and never ends
彼は年老いて終わりがない
But this old and final
しかし、この古くて最後の
He is in a hurry, everything is a disease
彼は急いでいる、すべてが病気だ
He said that this cancer from 100%
彼は、この癌は100％であると言いました
Up to now it is 100% and has been reduced to 30%
これまでは 100% でしたが、30% に削減されました。
Of course after 37% is resolved
もちろん37%が解決してから
The focus of his medical
彼の医療の焦点は、
where is he going to put it
彼はそれをどこに置くつもりですか
I think it might be above Laojihezhong
老司河中よりも上かもしれないと思う
Then the progress of our brain
そして私たちの脳の進歩
If he can solve human problems
彼が人類の問題を解決できるなら
then everyone is like a young man
そうすれば誰もが若者のようになる
Can be lively and dare to run and jump
活発で、果敢に走ったり、ジャンプしたりできる
that's a very good thing
それはとても良いことです
Thanks
ありがとう
Okay, are there any other questions on site?
さて、他に何か質問はありますか？
Hello teacher, I have a question
こんにちは、先生、質問があります
It's the old man who eats diarrhoea.
下痢食いのおっさんです。
Parkinson's disease is irreversible
パーキンソン病は回復不可能です
using drugs
薬物を使用する
It's just a delay
ただの遅れだよ
is that so
そうですか
That is to say, to delay the aggravation of the disease
つまり、病気の悪化を遅らせるということです。
Is it getting heavier all the time?
重くなってきましたか？
Is that how it works?
そういう仕組みなのでしょうか？
Yes, roughly speaking, it may be true.
はい、大まかに言えば、それは真実かもしれません。
But now I am most afraid of fitness disease
でも今一番怖いのはフィットネス病です
The latest treatment they're experimenting with is a modality
彼らが実験している最新の治療法はモダリティです
what japan is doing is to say
日本がやっていることは言うことだ
Hit stem cells to
幹細胞を攻撃する
stem cell
幹細胞
stem cell aging
幹細胞の老化
stem cells into the brain
幹細胞を脳に注入する
dopamine zone
ドーパミンゾーン
Then this can replenish new nerve cells
これにより、新しい神経細胞が補充されます
So this is no longer
だからこれはもうない
You can imagine that could be replaced by
これを次のものに置き換えることができると想像できます。
It's not just slowing down those nerve cells.
それは神経細胞の速度を低下させるだけではありません。
That is to say, fear of mental loss can be dealt with in this way.
つまり、精神的損失の恐怖はこの方法で対処できるのです。
in test
テスト中
they are testing
彼らはテスト中です
They are doing human experiments
彼らは人体実験を行っている
Then I always thought he was completely irreversible
それから私はいつも彼は完全に取り返しのつかないものだと思っていました
right
右
Thanks
ありがとう
Is that a human experiment?
それは人体実験ですか？
yes
はい
That's one of the Lobel speakers
それはLobelのスピーカーの1つです
their school
彼らの学校
he made that
彼はそれを作りました
IPS that
IPSそれ
what's that chinese name
その中国語の名前は何ですか
right
右
that stem cell therapy
その幹細胞療法
they lead that out of a
彼らはそれを
this nerve cell
この神経細胞
and then import it into the brain
そしてそれを脳にインポートします
then they this
それから彼らはこれを
This is much different from what China said just now.
これは中国が今言ったこととは大きく異なります。
they are strict
彼らは厳しいです
this test
このテスト
RB pair
RBペア
Then everything fits after
その後、すべてがうまくいきます
Dare to do this test like this
あえてこのテストをこのようにしてみます
Li Qingyun mentioned by the professor just now
先ほど先生がおっしゃった李清雲です。
on the internet
インターネット上で
means it's 256 years old
ということは256歳ということですね
then under the same circumstances
その後同じ状況で
can we find this
これを見つけられますか
It can live to be 256 years old
256歳まで生きる可能性がある
What about creating this same environment to increase human lifespan?
人間の寿命を延ばすためにこれと同じ環境を作るのはどうでしょうか？
Yes or no
はい、もしくは、いいえ
There are indeed several places in the world
確かに世界にはいくつかの場所があります
The average life expectancy of people is longer
人々の平均寿命は延びている
There is a longevity village in Japan, Italy or something
日本には長寿村がある、イタリアとか
So is it genetic or genetic?
それで、それは遺伝ですか、それとも遺伝ですか？
The relationship between the environment can actually be studied like this
実際に環境との関係はこうやって調べることができます
there is an average
平均があります
That is to say, you today, Li Qingyun, are alone
つまり、今日のあなた、李青雲は一人です
one example
一例
For us to do experiments and do science
私たちが実験や科学を行うために
N equals E is unreliable
N が E に等しい場合は信頼性がありません
We all want N equal to several
私たちは皆、N が数に等しいことを望んでいます。
We will say that this is preferable
これが望ましいと言えます
Then part of Li Qingyun should be
そうすると、Li Qingyun の一部は次のようになります。
I don't know if it should be a rumor
噂にするべきかどうかはわかりません
Because it's all word of mouth about this guy.
だってこの人のことは全部口伝えだから。
Some people say that my grandfather heard it when he was young
祖父が若い頃に聞いたという人もいる
Li Qingyun this person
李清雲この人
so to speak
いわば
Retweet and say that this was in the pre-dragon period
押し返して、これはドラゴン以前の時代だったと言う
Read it online, the story is very interesting and exciting
オンラインで読んでください、ストーリーはとても面白くてエキサイティングです
But then this this
でもそれからこれこれ
Newspapers are reporting this
新聞各紙がこれを報じている
But that New York Times 100 years ago
しかし、100年前のニューヨーク・タイムズ
Who knows if there will be false reports?
虚偽の報告があるかどうかは誰にも分かりません。
So you can go and see
だからあなたは行って見ることができます
as entertainment news
エンタメニュースとして
I think it's good
良いと思います
that's not to mislead people
それは人々を誤解させるためではありません
Okay, is there anyone here with any questions?
さて、何か質問のある人はいますか？
No, we have a network here
いいえ、ここにはネットワークがあります
Ask Mr. Jane what I have learned so far
これまでに学んだことをジェーンさんに聞いてください
Molecular Mechanisms of Artmap Degradation
アートマップ劣化の分子メカニズム
Causality with electrophysiological properties
電気生理学的特性との因果関係
is due to the degradation of the molecule
分子の分解によるものです
Does static ear cause the degradation of electrophysiological properties?
耳の静電気は電気生理学的特性の低下を引き起こしますか?
Or the electrophysiological changes will be reversed
あるいは電気生理学的変化が逆転するだろう
cause genetic changes
遺伝子変化を引き起こす
Both directions are possible
両方の方向が可能です
That is to say, its electrophysiological properties are basically
つまり、その電気生理学的特性は基本的には
Even the conduction in electrogenesis actually relies a lot on protein
電気発生における伝導でさえ、実際にはタンパク質に大きく依存しています
The Membrane protein channel on the cell surface
細胞表面の膜タンパク質チャネル
or something
か何か
Then there is a problem with these proteins, there is a problem with speed
これらのタンパク質には問題があり、スピードにも問題があります
then the protein decreases
するとタンパク質が減ってしまう
That will of course cause changes in the electrophysiology
それは当然電気生理学に変化を引き起こすでしょう
What's not normal in that electrician
電気技師はどうしたの
For example, a conduction that is too strong, conduction of electricity
例えば、強すぎる伝導、電気の伝導
That could also cause injury at the speed itself
スピードそのもので怪我をする可能性もある
Then I think both ways are possible
それなら両方の方法が可能だと思います
Okay, the second question is
さて、2番目の質問は
I would like to ask whether Parkinson's is the same as the general aging condition
パーキンソン病は一般的な老化現象と同じなのかどうか聞きたいです。
Is the molecular mechanism of his neurotic speed retreat different?
彼の神経質なスピード退却の分子メカニズムは異なるのでしょうか？
i think it's different
それは違うと思う
This can be seen that this found the gene
これにより、遺伝子が見つかったことがわかります
Parkinson's has genes like Parkinson's own
パーキンソン病にはパーキンソン病と同じような遺伝子がある
Alzheimer's this Alzheimer's this other kind of gene
アルツハイマー病 これもアルツハイマー病 これは別の種類の遺伝子
These genes are actually different
これらの遺伝子は実際には異なります
So it should be. I think the molecular mechanism may be different.
それもそのはず、分子機構が違うのではないかと思います。
Well, is there any problem at the scene?
さて、現場では何か問題があるのでしょうか？
i want to ask a question
私は質問をしたいです
Suppose the results of this experiment shown here
この実験の結果がここに示されていると仮定します
you give it gastrodia elata
あなたはそれを胃エラタに与えます
0.1% is very effective
0.1%でもかなり効果あり
Then 0.5% and 1% are not very effective
そうすると、0.5%や1%ではあまり効果がありません。
So does this mean that eating too much won't help?
ということは、食べ過ぎても効果がないということでしょうか？
right
右
that
それか
We've tried other bases and it's shown here
他のベースも試しましたが、それがここに表示されます
Its 0.02% doesn't do much either
0.02%でもあまり効果がありません
So swallowing it is actually 0.1% which is the most effective.
したがって、実際に飲み込むのは0.1％であり、これが最も効果的です。
Then we know that the reaction to this drug is often a
そして、この薬に対する反応はしばしば次のようなものであることがわかります。
Are they called U-SHIPs?
U-SHIPって言うんですか？
and then just about to
そしてまさにこれから
or a MERSH
またはマーシュ
MERSH by itself
マーシュ単体
Just the right amount of base is the best
ベースは適量がベスト
too little too much
少なすぎる
So we often say that you should follow the doctor's instructions to take medicine
ですから、薬は医師の指示に従ってくださいとよく言われます。
in this way
この上
Because of its high concentration of course
もちろん濃度が高いので
It may act on other molecules
他の分子に作用する可能性があります
If there is too little, it may not be enough.
少なすぎると物足りないかも知れません。
So this is a
これは
yes
はい
So this result is actually grandson, you ask me
つまり、この結果は実際には孫なのです、あなたは私に尋ねますか？
Don't take it by yourself when you go home
家に帰るときは一人で取らないでください
too much can be problematic
多すぎると問題が発生する可能性があります
Okay, the last one will ask you later
はい、最後の人は後で質問します
Excuse me, professor, you just said
教授に聞いてもいいですか、あなたは今言いました
When you use Pegasus
ペガサスを使うときは
It is the use of scientifically concentrated traditional Chinese medicine
科学的に濃縮された伝統的な中国医学の使用です。
extraction
抽出
yes
はい
we all try
私たちは皆試します
Concentrated
濃縮
then additionally
それから追加で
This experiment proved that concentrated
この実験は、集中力があることを証明しました。
We have put the principal components inside
主要コンポーネントを内部に配置しました
called Gasodin
ガソディンと呼ばれる
tried
試してみた
that works too
それも機能します
But not as good as this
しかし、これほど良くはありません
so it looks like
だからそれはのように見える
It's actually several ingredients together
実際にはいくつかの成分が一緒になっています
It might work best like this
こういうのが一番うまくいくかもしれない
ask one more
もう一つ聞いてください
Just happened to be right
たまたま正しかっただけ
just now your slime shows
今あなたのスライムが現れました
There are more sketches about the autism
自閉症に関するスケッチは他にもあります
Sutu
スツ
Then Lomo's normal down
それからロモは通常通りダウンします
Then the other one is called
次に、もう一方が呼び出されます
mental disorder
思覺失調
I'm just wondering if autistic people are less likely to get treatment from Bakis
自閉症の人はバキスの治療を受ける可能性が低いのかどうか疑問に思っています
Relatively speaking
相対的に言えば
this is a good question
これは良い質問です
I'm guessing
推測します
I never thought about this
こんなこと考えたこともなかった
That fear is like this in this life
その恐怖はこの世ではこんな感じ
For example, for some diseases, sometimes some investigations will find that this is indeed the case
たとえば、一部の病気では、調査によってこれが実際に当てはまることが判明する場合があります。
Even before, there was a person who taught the most general way of speaking
以前にも、最も一般的な話し方を教えた人がいた
That means people with cancer don't get that
つまり、がん患者にはそれが受けられないということです
Neural push
ニューラルプッシュ
You won't get cancer if you get nervous
緊張すると癌にならないよ
Then they came up with a theory
それから彼らはある理論を思いつきました
this one with protein
これはプロテイン入り
folding is related
折りたたみが関係してる
Protein folding is related to
タンパク質のフォールディングには以下のことが関係しています。
Even if this life has something to do with Alzheimer's disease
たとえこの人生がアルツハイマー病と関係があるとしても
Protect
保護
There are some things that are actually being investigated now
実際に現在調査中のものもある
Some factors have had an impact on him.
いくつかの要因が彼に影響を与えた。
full of effect
効果がいっぱい
some effect
何らかの効果
The greatest effect on the two diseases
2つの病気に対する最大の効果
is age
年齢です
The best age to talk about now
伝えるのに最適な年齢
The older you get, the higher your memory of getting sick
年齢を重ねるほど、病気の記憶が強くなる
The second most effective thing is exercise
次に効果的なのは運動です
Most sports have a great effect on this
ほとんどのスポーツはこれに大きな影響を与えます
There are some reasons that I can't tell
言えない理由もあるけど
For example, drinking coffee is actually right
たとえば、コーヒーを飲むのは実は正しいことなのです
Mr Pan has some effect
パン氏には何らかの影響がある
But the effect is very small, so don't write it down
ただし効果は非常に小さいので書かないでください
Go back and drink more?
戻ってもっと飲みますか？
can't sleep at night
夜眠れない
Then there is another one that everyone is afraid to say
それから、誰もが言うことを恐れているもう一つのことがあります
is smoking
喫煙しています
Once you talk about it, it will be troublesome
一度話したら面倒になるよ
People who smoke say I have a reason to smoke
タバコを吸う人たちは、私にはタバコを吸う理由があると言います
Well, if you actually smoke, that's right.
まあ、実際に喫煙するなら、それは正しいです。
Alzheimer's and Mr. Pan have a little protective effect
アルツハイマー病とミスター・パンにはわずかな保護効果がある
This is also your game to read literature
これは文学を読むゲームでもあります
But everyone is afraid to speak, sorry to speak
でもみんな話すのが怖い、話すのはごめんなさい
I'm talking secretly now, please don't say that
今こっそり話してます、そんなこと言わないでください
please don't promote
宣伝しないでください
But in fact there are reporters
でも実際には記者がいる
Let me add that this type of research is all about correlation
この種の研究は相関関係がすべてであることを付け加えておきます。
who you statistically smoke
統計的に誰を吸うのか
What are the odds of getting this?
これを入手できる確率はどれくらいですか?
It's not about smoking
喫煙の話じゃないよ
will affect this matter
この問題に影響を与えるだろう
OK, are we still there?
はい、まだいますか？
friends have problems
友達が問題を抱えている
please
お願いします
That is, there are three nerves on the edge of the four nerves
つまり、4本の神経の端に3本の神経があるということです。
just mentioned three
先ほど3つ挙げました
one is that shape
一つはその形です
on the edge
縁に
one is color
1つは色です
Then another judgment is his dynamic
そして、別の判断は彼の力学です
that such a
そんなこと
Is it because his body's four nerves have different divisions of labor?
それは彼の体の4つの神経が異なる役割分担をしているからでしょうか？
Are there any that are more sensitive to color?
もっと色に敏感なものはありますか？
Is there any division of labor in these nerve borders?
これらの神経境界には役割分担があるのでしょうか？
Or is it that the entire nerve border of our tetraretina is
それとも四網膜の神経境界全体が損傷しているのでしょうか？
Same work and same hatred
同じ仕事、同じ憎しみ
and then add different dimensions
そして、さまざまなディメンションを追加します
you asked a good question
あなたは良い質問をしました
I'm not an expert there
私はその分野の専門家ではありません
But I can give you some simple answers
しかし、いくつかの簡単な答えを与えることができます
The first one is called parallel processing
1つ目は並列処理と呼ばれるものです
is processed together
一緒に処理される
They do divide labor
それらはまさに分業です
look at the color
色を見てください
The color is also divided into red green blue
色も赤・緑・青に分かれています
three colors
三色
red is only for humans
赤は人間だけのもの
You go to some monkeys or to the general east house that red is gone
あなたはサルの所に行くか、東の家に行くと赤が消えています
So we humans can see roses
だから私たち人間はバラを見ることができるのです
beautiful roses
美しいバラ
That
それか
then that
それからそれ
are different four nerves far in
遠く離れた4つの神経は異なります
look at different things
さまざまなものを見てください
then put together
それから一緒にします
So our eyes are actually very powerful
私たちの目は実は非常に強力です
Sorry to add a related
関連追加してすみません
because i teach art
私は美術を教えているので
Then it seems that boys are less sensitive to social feelings
そうすると、男の子は社会的感情に鈍感になるようです
right
右
then to that
それからそこへ
in shape
形で
they have a good grasp
彼らはよく理解している
is a boy
男の子です
you go to the department store
あなたはデパートに行きます
Boys, look what you all wear
少年たち、みんなが着ているものを見てください
It's those colors
それはそれらの色です
keep it simple
単純にする
Then they say women are more like children
それから女性は子供に似ていると言われます
That color is very colorful
その色はとてもカラフルです
And there will be a very detailed analysis
そして非常に詳細な分析が行われます
It's also a human
それも人間です
A division of labor for the development of an entire culture
文化全体の発展のための分業
some are
いくつかは
Demon offers nerves to destroy it
悪魔はそれを破壊するために神経を提供します
just don't be too sensitive
ただあまり敏感にならないでください
I can say this, it's not good for boys, it's not good for girls
これは言える、それは男の子にも良くないし、女の子にも良くない
We have a gene that recognizes red, it seems to be X
私たちは赤を認識する遺伝子を持っています、それはXであるようです
If you know X, there is only one for boys and two for girls
X を知っているなら、男の子には 1 つ、女の子には 2 つしかありません
This boy is prone to mutations, so boys have a lot of color
この少年は突然変異を起こしやすいので、少年は性欲が強いです
Some people are more sensitive to color, in fact, the photoreceptor cells
実際、光受容細胞の色に対してより敏感な人もいます。
That is to say, apart from recognizing red, he may have a little difference in length
つまり、赤を認識する以外に、長さにも少し違いがある可能性があります
He may have different neurons to detect him
彼は彼を検出するための異なるニューロンを持っている可能性があります
So some people are really sensitive to those who study art or clothes design like you
ですから、あなたのようにアートや服飾デザインを勉強している人たちにとても敏感な人もいます。
like us , like me is very insensitive
私たちと同じように、私と同じように非常に鈍感です
I probably only do experiments to see red, green and blue mixed together like this
たぶん、こうやって赤、緑、青が混ざり合う実験しかしてないんだろうな
Then there is indeed a natural difference
そうすれば、確かに自然な違いが存在します
As I mentioned just now, there are also animals, some of which cannot see red
さっきも言いましたが、動物の中には赤が見えない動物もいます。
ok , we are running out of time , our last question
さて、時間がなくなりました、最後の質問です
I can add to the lady's question just now
今の女性の質問に追加できます
She didn't mean that we were...
彼女は私たちがそうであるという意味ではありませんでした...
Our nerve cells have a division of labor on the image
私たちの神経細胞は画像に関して分業を行っています
My answer is to try
私の答えは、試してみることです
Then its division of labor
次にその分業
The color is that there is a kind of sight-seeking cells on our social membrane.
その色は、私たちの社会膜に一種の視覚を求める細胞があることを示しています。
It can identify RGB three colors
RGB3色を識別可能
There should be this related connection in fine arts
美術界にもこの関連性があるはずだ
So we can identify RGB
したがって、RGBを識別できます
Then use its brightness's
次に、その明るさを使用します
It is to disassemble it to show our various colors
分解して様々な色を見せることです
Then in terms of pure brightness
では純粋な明るさという点では
There is another type called sight-seeking cells
照準細胞と呼ばれる別のタイプもあります
it can be compared for brightness
明るさを比較できる
And finally the part of that shape
そして最後にその形の部分
Mainly when some visual areas of the brain are doing calculations
主に脳の一部の視覚領域が計算を行っているとき
it will have specific different cells
特定の異なるセルが含まれます
is to analyze its shape or the direction it moves
その形状や移動方向を分析することです
then activates a specific population of cells in the visual area
次に、視覚野の特定の細胞集団を活性化します。
Do more advanced processing
より高度な処理を行う
Thanks
ありがとう
ok thank you very well said
わかりました、ありがとうございます
ok then i think our time is up
はい、もう時間切れだと思います
Thank you for your enthusiastic participation today
本日は熱心にご参加いただきましてありがとうございました
Hope we can come again in December
12月にまた来れるといいですね
Thanks
ありがとう